<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_ASSYRIA_DESC">
			<Text>Assyrian Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_ASSYRIA_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Assyria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TCM_ASSYRIA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Assyrian</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DOM_TCM_ASSYRIA_TEXT">
			<Text>Eternal glory be yours, O legendary empress of Assyria, the fabled Semiramis! From the rivers of the levant to the peaks of the Caucasus people grovel to your name, and marvel at your unrelenting spirit and inexorable passion. And though the feats of your rule have since faded to time, forever will your character be ingrained in the memories and legends of the resilient Assyrian people who stand to this day.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Indomitable Empress, while it is true that your people still endure, they are without nation, cast aside from their glorious past as masters of the middle east. O Sammuramat, will you resume your steadfast rule and build a new empire for them to surpass all others? Will you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_TITLE">
			<Text>Assyria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The many ancient kingdoms of Assyria, long since swept into the dust of history, were at various times among the most prosperous and powerful of any on Earth. Centered in the heart of Mesopotamia (modern northern Iraq), Assyria was founded by Semitic descendants of Akkadian and Sumerian refugees following the collapse of the Akkadian Empire c. 2154 BC, whose languages and customs slowly coalesced into two distinct Mesopotamian peoples: the Assyrians in the north and Babylonians in the south. Despite a number of initial attempts at forming an independent kingdom, the Assyrians were continually thwarted by the expansion of their neighbors, particularly Babylon. Eventually, commencing with the near-legendary Tudiya, Assyrian kings succeeded in establishing a great empire - and on more than one occasion Assyria was the most powerful state in the region. However, Assyria also continued to suffer at the hands of neighboring rivals, and by the late 6th Century BC, the empire was no more.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Climate and Terrain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Located in the fertile region of Mesopotamia around the Tigris-Euphrates river system, Assyria lay in a land capable of producing bountiful harvests of wheat and other grains. Widely considered to be the cradle of Western civilization, in the Bronze Age Mesopotamia was dominated by the Sumerian, Akkadian, Babylonian and Assyrian cultures. The climate of Assyria was semi-arid, although the kingdom received ample water in the form of snowmelt and rain from the Zagros Mountains throughout the year. The river region (some 5800 square miles) is marked by marshes, lagoons, mud flats and reed banks. Irrigated agriculture spread south from the Zagros foothills commencing around 5000 BC; Assyrian farmers are known to have planted such crops as wheat, barley, onions, grapes, turnips and apples. The land that once constituted the Assyrian homeland is now primarily encompassed by parts of Syria, Iran, Iraq and Turkey. Bordered to the north by rugged mountains, to the west by the Aramaeans, to the south by the kingdoms of Babylonia and Elam and the Amorite tribes of Arabia, the Assyrians were in a fruitful but tenuous position.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Early People</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_TEXT_3">
			<Text>The oldest Neolithic sites in Assyria date to c. 7100 BC, and the earliest evidence of human culture, the Hassuna culture, to c. 6000 BC. The region that would encompass Assyria is home to the first known examples of irrigated agriculture, and to some of the earliest human settlements. Among these can be included Assur, which was founded at some point in the mid-3rd millennium BC; it appears to have been an administrative center for Sumaria rather than an independent city. Nineveh, although likely established far earlier, is first mentioned in historical records in 1800 BC as the center of worship for Ishtar, the primary deity of Mesopotamia.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the third and second millenniums BC, a cultural symbiosis between the Sumerians and Semites gave rise to the Akkadian empire, of which the Assyrian cities were a vital element. The list of Assyrian kings, commencing with Tudiya, begins with the fall of the Akkadian empire, destroyed by internal strife, economic collapse and the incursions of barbarians. However, after a brief period of independence, the Assyrian lands were absorbed by the Third Sumerian Empire of Ur, which had been founded in 2112 BC. From the decline of the Akkadian and subsequently the Sumerian empires, a distinct Assyrian culture emerged to establish customs and traditions of their own, coinciding with crucial technological developments in agriculture, animal husbandry, pottery, and metal working.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_HEADING_4">
			<Text>First Assyrian Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Although the ancient Assyrian "King List" records many early kings, dating back as far as the 19th Century BC, the earliest Assyrian king for whom any definitive historical context exists was King Shamshi-Adad I, who ruled the city of Assur and established Assyrian control over much of Mesopotamia. He had deposed the Akkadian ruler of Assyria in 1813 BC and proclaimed himself the new king. Shortly thereafter, Shamshi-Adad began a campaign of expansion. He placed one of his sons on the throne of the nearby city of Ekallatum, and reestablished authority over Assyria's small Anatolian colonies. He next conquered the kingdom of Mari along the Euphrates, placing another son on the throne there.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Shamshi-Adad retired to oversee construction of a new capital city for himself, but died c. 1790 BC before it was completed. His sons fared poorly thereafter. The younger was overthrown by a rebellion in Mari, whose new king promptly allied himself with the king Hammurabi, who was in the process of making the newly-created kingdom of Babylon a major military power. The Babylonian forces swept into Assyria, overwhelming several cities. With Hammurabi's support, the Anatolian cities revolted and broke away from the Assyrian kingdom. Finally, the Babylonian king conquered Ekallatum itself, and the first fledgling Assyrian Empire fell and was fully absorbed into Babylon by 1756 BC. However, the bloodline of Assyrian kings survived as vassals to Hammurabi.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Assyrian Resurgence</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Hammurabi's short-lived empire rapidly unraveled following his death c. 1750 BC, and Babylon lost control over Assyria during the reign of his immediate successor. Commencing with the overthrow of an Amorite king ruling Assyria for Babylon by the vice-regent Puzur-Sin, the country plunged into a period of unrest and civil war, marked by relatively short reigns by the Assyrian kings. In the 16th Century BC, the Mittani - an Indo-European people - overran Anatolia and pushed eastwards, capturing and sacking Assur around 1480 BC. The Assyrian monarchy survived as vassals, and the Mittani appear to have been content to avoid interference in internal Assyrian affairs so long as tribute was paid.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]By the reign of Eriba-Adad I (1390-1366 BC), Mittani power had declined significantly and his successor, Ashur-uballit, spent his years making Assyria an empire again. Having defeated the Hurrians and the Hittites to end any threat from that quarter, Ashur-uballit married his daughter to the last Kassite king of Babylon. When the Babylonian king was murdered by an unruly political faction, Ashur-uballit promptly invaded and absorbed Babylon. Shortly after he moved against the Mittani, crushing their forces despite military support for them from the Hittites and Hurrians. The lands of the Mittani and the Hurrians were appropriated, making Assyria a large and powerful kingdom once again.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Over the next two centuries, an unbroken succession of able kings insured the prosperity and stability of the kingdom, making it the dominant power in Mesopotamia. Internal reforms and policies maintained their popularity among the people and nobles, while a sequence of victories expanded Assyrian holdings into Asia Minor and the Levant. In 1274 BC, the great warrior king Shalmaneser I ascended the throne, pushing the boundaries of the Assyrian empire into the Caucasus Mountains and overrunning eastern Anatolia. At its peak, the empire stretched from the shores of the Persian Gulf to those of the Mediterranean. But following the death of emperor Tilgath-Pileser I, Assyria entered a 300-year period of decline.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_HEADING_6">
			<Text>A Dark Age</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_TEXT_6">
			<Text>Mesopotamia entered a "Dark Ages" (dated c. 1200-900 BC) as less-civilized peoples overran much of the region. Semitic peoples such as the Arameans and Chaldeans nibbled at the western and southern borders of the Assyrian Empire, conquering much of Babylon. The Medes and Persians swept into the lands east of the Assyrian heartland. To the north, the Phrygians overran the Hittites and Armenian tribes pushed the Assyrians out of the Caucasus. Cimmerians and Scythians began migrations outward from their Black Sea homelands. Assyrian kings during this time seem to have contented themselves with defending a compact area centered on Assur and Nineveh and the trading center of Nimrud, surrendering the outer areas and colonies to the inevitable. They largely limited their military adventures to sporadic punitive raids against these barbarians, interspersed with the occasional effort at re-conquest of lost territories. Nonetheless these efforts slowly transformed Assyria into a warrior culture, even as trade collapsed and religion flourished. Anshur became the state god, and the priesthood rose to be a major political power in the kingdom, culminating in the murder of king Tukulti-ninurta I.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_HEADING_7">
			<Text>Neo-Assyrian Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_TEXT_7">
			<Text>The resurgence of Assyrian influence begins with the accession of Adad-nirani II in 911 BC. This "Neo-Assyrian" Empire would survive until the fall of Nineveh in 612 BC to an allied force of Babylonians, Medes, Scythians and Cimmerians. At its zenith, around 671 BC, the empire would reach from the Nile River across northern Arabia to the Persian Gulf, north to the Zargos and Caucasus mountain ranges, and deep into Asia Minor in the west. It would cover all or portions of the present-day nations of Iraq, Iran, Georgia, Turkey, Armenia, Syria, Jordan, Israel, Kuwait, Egypt and Saudi Arabia - the largest empire yet seen in human history.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Beginning with the campaigns of Adad-nirani, Assyria subjugated the border territories and vassals that had seen only nominal Assyrian authority for a century. King Adad-nirani I then proceeded to conquer troublesome Aramean, neo-Hittite and Hurrian populations to the north. It was at this point that he instituted the state policy of deporting and resettling new subject peoples to other parts of the Assyrian empire, a ruthless policy his successors would follow. In the last years of his reign, he launched a successful campaign against Babylonia.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Upon Adad-Nirani's death in 892 BC, his heir would consolidate these gains as well as conquer the Persian and Medean settlements in the Zargos Mountains. Subsequent rulers would use the revitalized Assyrian military, notably its siege engines (which were particularly effective against mud-brick city walls), to great benefit as they overran vast tracts in the Arabian Peninsula, Asia Minor and Mesopotamia itself. Even the queens pursued Assyrian expansion. When Adad-nirani III (810-782 BC) came to the throne he was a small boy; his mother, semi-legendary queen Semiramis, serving as regent, crushed the last holdings of the Medes and Persians for the empire before abdicating power to her son after a few years.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Following a brief period of peace, expansion continued apace under Adad-nirani's successors in an unbroken string of conquests. Tiglath-pileser III (who reigned 745-727 BC), Sargon II (722-705), and the ruthlessly-effective Sennacherib (705-681) would add Phoenicia, Israel, Judah, Samaria, Palestine, Cyprus, Moab and vast tracts in the Taurus Mountains and the Arabian Peninsula to the empire. Sennacherib's heir Esarhaddon crossed the Sinai Desert to invade Egypt, driving its Nubian rulers out and, in the process, destroying the Kushite Empire. Returning to Assyria, Esarhaddon began the rebuilding of the city of Babylon which had been leveled following a revolt but died while preparing another invasion of Egypt.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Esarhaddon's death in 669 BC brought Ashurbanipal, considered to be the greatest of neo-Assyria's emperors, to the throne. Although more concerned with reform and scholarship, Ashurbanipal proved a capable warrior as well. Although he spent much of his time suppressing revolts and border incursions, he also completed the conquest of Egypt, the last expansion of the neo-Assyrian Empire. However, Ashurbanipal is best known for his efforts to rebuild cities, sponsor advances in Assyrian arts and sciences, and establish libraries throughout the realm. The cuneiform and scribal texts found by archeologists in his great palace library in Nineveh have provided much of what is known of not only Assyria but the entire region during this era.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_HEADING_8">
			<Text>Collapse</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_TEXT_8">
			<Text>Following the death of Ashurbanipal in 627 BC, a number of short-lived rival successors claimed the throne; Assyria was thrust into a period of civil war. The disarray and devastation brought by these conflicts led directly to the decline and dissolution of not only the Assyrian Empire, but also to the culture distinctly identified as "Assyria." In 605 BC, an alliance of Babylonians and Medes would defeat an Assyrian-Egyptian force at Carchemish and Assyria would become a Babylonian province. Following the collapse of the Baylonian Empire, the traditional Assyrian homeland would be overrun by waves of invaders ranging from the Persians through the Arabs. Knowledge of its glories and works would virtually disappear until brought to light by modern archeologists and historians, beginning with the excavations of fabled Nineveh in 1845 AD.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_HEADING_9">
			<Text>Factoids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_ASSYRIA_TEXT_9">
			<Text>Neo-Assyrian emperors would deport thousands of people to insure pacification of newly-conquered kingdoms, continuing a policy instituted by the first emperor Adad-nirani II. Among the most infamous of these forced resettlements: 65,000 from Persian lands to the Assyrian-Babylonian border in 744BC; 108,000 Babylonians and Chaldeans to the western frontier in 707 BC; and in 703 BC emperor Sennacherib ordered the scattering of 208,000 residents of Babylon across the empire.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_01">
			<Text>Nimrud</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_02">
			<Text>Assur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_03">
			<Text>Nineveh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_04">
			<Text>Babylon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_05">
			<Text>Kar-Tukulti-Ninurta</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_06">
			<Text>Dur-Sharrukin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_07">
			<Text>Halab</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_08">
			<Text>Carchemish</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_09">
			<Text>Harran</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_10">
			<Text>Imgur-Enlil</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_11">
			<Text>Nippur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_12">
			<Text>Kish</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_13">
			<Text>Shubat-Enlil</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_14">
			<Text>Turuspa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_15">
			<Text>Qatna</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_16">
			<Text>Sareisa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_17">
			<Text>Sam al</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_18">
			<Text>Tarsisi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_19">
			<Text>Til Barsip</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_20">
			<Text>Sultantepe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_21">
			<Text>Opis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_22">
			<Text>Erbil</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_23">
			<Text>Erech</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_24">
			<Text>Hamath</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_25">
			<Text>Guzana</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_26">
			<Text>Nasibina</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_27">
			<Text>Arpad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_28">
			<Text>Kelashin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_29">
			<Text>Sabata</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_30">
			<Text>Hit</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_0">
			<Text>Ninus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_1">
			<Text>Onnes</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_2">
			<Text>Ara</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_3">
			<Text>Shamshi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_4">
			<Text>Nimrod</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_5">
			<Text>Sonanê</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_6">
			<Text>Abella</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_7">
			<Text>Kubaba</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_8">
			<Text>Atargatis</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TCM_ASSYRIA_9">
			<Text>Tiamat</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PEDIA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PEDIA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Sammuramat was an empress regnant of Assyria between 811 and 808 BCE, or from 809 to 792 BCE according to soe. The wife of King Shamshi-Adad, she ruled the Neo-Assyrian Empire as its regent for five years or more until her son Adad-nirari III came of age. She was one of the first known women to rule an empire, thus many legends are associated to her, including that of Semiramis, the legendary wife of King Ninus who supposedly ruled Mesopotamia, Anatolia, Egypt, Lybia, Aethiopia, Iran, Caucasus, Bactria and launched invasions against India.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PEDIA_LIVED">
			<Text>Unknown</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PEDIA_NAME">
			<Text>Sammuramat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PEDIA_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Assyria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PEDIA_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Empress-Regnant</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT">
			<Text>Sammuramat</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ASSYRIA_SHORT">
			<Text>Tale of Semiramis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ASSYRIA">
			<Text>Upon capturing a World Wonder, retrigger its one-time effect. Gain [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production when someone builds a World Wonder if you have an embassy with them, per leader than doesn't.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TCM_EKALLU">
			<Text>Royal Ekallu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TCM_EKALLU_HELP">
			<Text>If produced by expending a Great Engineer, the Royal Ekallu generates +5 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness. Generates +3 Great Engineer points per city being [ICON_RAZING] Razed on the empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TCM_EKALLU_STRATEGY">
			<Text>By setting up a Royal Ekallu without a Great Engineer beforehand, you can establish a constant flow of engineer points by conquering other civilizations which will allow you to build +5 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] generating Royal Ekallus in his cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_TCM_EKALLU_TEXT">
			<Text>Like other civilizations around mesopotamia, the Assyrians were able to build marvelous constructions of huge size. The Assyrians enjoyed filling them with paintings of the current king butchering rebel and razing cities to the ground to terrorize any visitors to their palaces.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TCM_SAPPER_UNIT">
			<Text>Sapper</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_TCM_SAPPER_UNIT">
			<Text>Spearman replacement unique to Assyria. Gains XP when fortified around an enemy city and may expend a Promotion to heavily damage it. +100% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength vs. cities if stacked with a Great Engineer.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TCM_SAPPER_UNIT_STRATEGY">
			<Text>An extremely aggressive Spearman replaces that lacks strength and bonus against mounted units, but makes up for it by being extremely effective at sieging cities. Use it together with a Great Engineer to bring your enemies to submission!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_TCM_SAPPER_UNIT_TEXT">
			<Text>The Assyrians experienced with numerous methods to taking cities, from cheap ladders to massive siege towers. One of these methods was to send specialized infantry units to dig and destabilize the enemy walls, causing them to collapse.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GENERIC_TCM_ASSYRIA_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">
			<Text>Our people are now drinking your Arak and dancing the Khigga. I worry the rest of the world will also succumb to the influence of your culture.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- E&D -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_TCM_ASSYRIA_BANKS_BABYLON">
			<Text>Raise the River Banks of Babylon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_TCM_ASSYRIA_BANKS_BABYLON_DESC">
			<Text>
				What the plains of Mesopotamia can give, they also take away; every year comes the rain, and every year it floods everything on its path. But now we have mastered the secrets of engineering and with an united people, we can beat such indomitable waters. Nature itself will be conquered by us! Let us build canals and embankments to become masters of these rivers!
				[NEWLINE]
				[NEWLINE]Requirement/Restrictions:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Player must be Assyria (Sammuramat)
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]May only be enacted once per game
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Must have researched Engineering
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Must have a river city
				[NEWLINE]Costs:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]{1_GoldCost} [ICON_GOLD] Gold
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]1 [ICON_MAGISTRATES] Magistrates
				[NEWLINE]Rewards:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]River cities yield +2 [ICON_FOOD] Food
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Gain {2_FoodGift} [ICON_FOOD] Food in all cities
				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]Note: The [ICON_GOLD] Gold cost and [ICON_FOOD] Food awarded increases with the number of river cities
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_TCM_ASSYRIA_BANKS_BABYLON_ENACTED_DESC">
			<Text>
				What the plains of Mesopotamia can give, they also take away; every year comes the rain, and every year it floods everything on its path. But now we have mastered the secrets of engineering and with an united people, we can beat such indomitable waters. Nature itself will be conquered by us! Let us build canals and embankments to become masters of these rivers!
				[NEWLINE]
				[NEWLINE]Rewards:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]River cities yield +2 [ICON_FOOD] Food
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_TCM_ASSYRIA_VICTORY_STELE">
			<Text>Erect Victory Stele</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_TCM_ASSYRIA_VICTORY_STELE_DESC">
			<Text>
				The Assyrian Empire, and whomever might ever rise to surpass it must never forget about the great conquests of our time. By erecting a mighty Victory Stele, such glorious additions to our empire will be ingrained in the minds of generations to come, and all will know that you, Sammuramat, ruled these lands!
				[NEWLINE]
				[NEWLINE]Requirement/Restrictions:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Player must be Assyria (Sammuramat)
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]May be enacted once per foreign [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital captured
				[NEWLINE]Costs:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]{1_GoldCost} [ICON_GOLD] Gold
				[NEWLINE]Rewards:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Monuments generate 1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Your [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital gains one extra Monument
				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]Note: [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness from monuments do not increase more than once
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_TCM_ASSYRIA_VICTORY_STELE_ENACTED_DESC">
			<Text>
				The Assyrian Empire, and whomever might ever rise to surpass it must never forget about the great conquests of our time. By erecting a mighty Victory Stele, such glorious additions to our empire will be ingrained in the minds of generations to come, and all will know that you, Sammuramat, ruled these lands!
				[NEWLINE]
				[NEWLINE]Rewards:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Monuments generate +1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness
				[ICON_BULLET]Your [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital gains one extra Monument
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_HANDSOME_SOLDIER">
			<Text>A Handsome Soldier</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_HANDSOME_SOLDIER_DESC">
			<Text>
				Your advisors let out a sigh immediatelly. As soon as you heard about the tale of a handsome {1_civAdjective} soldier, they knew you could not be swayed from this desire. You had to make him your lover, or else! And he dared thus far to spurn all your advances...[NEWLINE]
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_HANDSOME_SOLDIER_OUTCOME_1">
			<Text>I tire of this game!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_HANDSOME_SOLDIER_OUTCOME_2">
			<Text>Hah! I shall have him.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_HANDSOME_SOLDIER_OUTCOME_RESULT_1">
			<Text>
				[ICON_BULLET][COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]Declares war upon {1_CityState}[ENDCOLOR][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Gains two military units[ENDCOLOR]
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_HANDSOME_SOLDIER_OUTCOME_RESULT_2">
			<Text>[ICON_BULLET][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]66% chance to gain an extremely experienced military unit[ENDCOLOR]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TCM_ASSYRIA_HANDSOME_SOLDIER_OUTCOME_RESULT_1_NOTIFICATION">
			<Text>The warrior was not impressed by you! You shall take him by force, then...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TCM_ASSYRIA_HANDSOME_SOLDIER_OUTCOME_RESULT_2_NOTIFICATION_A">
			<Text>Sammuramat spent the night far away from her palace, leaving the court wondering...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TCM_ASSYRIA_HANDSOME_SOLDIER_OUTCOME_RESULT_2_NOTIFICATION_B">
			<Text>Despite your best efforts, the {1_civAdjective} hero was not impressed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WORLD_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_HANDSOME_SOLDIER_1">
			<Text>A warrior from {1_CityState} has spurned Sammuramat, who now marches onto his lands to capture him.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WORLD_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_HANDSOME_SOLDIER_2_A">
			<Text>Sammuramat has seduced an Hero from {1_CityState}, who joined her court.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WORLD_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_HANDSOME_SOLDIER_2_B">
			<Text>A warrior from {1_CityState} has spurned Sammuramat lewd advances.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_DECOY_SOLDIERS">
			<Text>Decoy Soldiers</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_DECOY_SOLDIERS_DESC">
			<Text>
				You have come up with an ingenious idea to deceive our enemies on the battlefield. We shall arrange woodwork in the form of soldiers and mighty war beasts and clad them in armor near the enemy troops, striking fear on their hearts and watch as they flee in terror from our toys![NEWLINE]
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_DECOY_SOLDIERS_OUTCOME_1">
			<Text>They will never see it coming.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_EVENT_TCM_ASSYRIA_DECOY_SOLDIERS_OUTCOME_RESULT_1">
			<Text>[ICON_BULLET][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Gain three fear-inducing military units who cannot attack[ENDCOLOR]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TCM_ASSYRIA_DECOY_SOLDIERS_OUTCOME_RESULT_1_NOTIFICATION">
			<Text>The decoys are ready! Send them to our enemies and watch them as they despair.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_LITERAL_DUMMY">
			<Text>Decoy Soldiers</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_LITERAL_DUMMY_HELP">
			<Text>Cannot attack but decreases the [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength of adjacent enemies and can soak up damage</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_SAPPING">
			<Text>Sapping</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_SAPPING_HELP">
			<Text>This unit is eligible to receive a promotion that deals damage to the adjacent city</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_SAPPING_2">
			<Text>Mine the Walls!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_SAPPING_2_HELP">
			<Text>Deals damage to an adjacent city</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_BATTLE_ENGINEER">
			<Text>Battle Great Engineer</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TCM_BATTLE_ENGINEER_HELP">
			<Text>+150% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength vs. Cities</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- DIPLOMACY: VANILLA Vanilla -->
		<!--First Greeting messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Oh my, I can see myself enjoy this very much. Say, how much time can you be staying here in Assyria?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>By Atargatis, who is this lovely one who just entered my palace? Tell me, how are you enjoying the sight? No, silly, I'm not talking about the city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Defeated messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>This is not so bad, not so bad at all. I'm still alive, so are you; I am sure we can come to an arrangement... Don't you think?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--First Greeting from leaders that don't have their own file yet-->
		<!-- Human repeats an action too much, gets the following responses -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_REPEAT_TOO_MUCH">
			<Text>It's cute to see you babble the same words over and over again... Do I make you uncomfortable?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_REPEAT_TRADE_1">
			<Text>How about you give me a litte bit more than that... ?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_REPEAT_TRADE_2">
			<Text>I can't accept such a deal right now. How about we have some drinks first, and talk about that tomorrow?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_REPEAT_TRADE_3">
			<Text>You'll have to do a bit more if you want to get that from me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_REPEAT_1">
			<Text>Back to see me again? I am flattered.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_REPEAT_2">
			<Text>Oh, you've come back for more?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_HOSTILE_REPEAT_1">
			<Text>I do wonder what you come here so much for. Oh, other than THAT of course.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_HOSTILE_REPEAT_2">
			<Text>You again? I should start charging for this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Greetings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Oh my dearest... Friend, I was wondering when you would show up again. Care to accompany me to some more private quarters?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Oh my, you have returned. I was longing for this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_3">
			<Text>Come to see me, or do business? The two can very well be interchangeable, you know...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_4">
			<Text>Dear one, for you I always have time to lend much more than just an ear.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_5">
			<Text>You're here, how exciting! Now, shall we... ?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_6">
			<Text>Aw, you came to see me again! I'll surely return the favor.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Hmm, you're back here. Came to turn things even more exciting?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_2">
			<Text>Is that a dagger on your pocket or are you happy to see me?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_DESTRUCTION_LOOMS_1">
			<Text>The end is near. I hope you graciously spare me, for I can be quite useful, you know well...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_DESTRUCTION_LOOMS_2">
			<Text>Mmh hmm, you have bested me. I'll accept any terms you come bringing... Any whatsoever... Anything you think that suits me...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_AT_WAR_WANTS_PEACE_1">
			<Text>Oh sweetie, shouldn't we finish this war already? I'm missing those old days...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_AT_WAR_WANTS_PEACE_2">
			<Text>Please, let's finish off here. I've been way too long without you around now.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_AT_WAR_WANTS_PEACE_3">
			<Text>Why don't we both just call our armies back and celebrate the return of peace together? What else could you want?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_AT_WAR_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>Hey, I'm still having fun here. I think I still can go on a couple of days without you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_AT_WAR_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>Tired already? I hope your lack of stamina is only for war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_AT_WAR_HOSTILE_3">
			<Text>What, you want to end the fun already?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_BROKEN_MILITARY_PROMISE_1">
			<Text>What business does a dishonorable individual such as yourself have here? Ahaha who am I kidding, this is the right place for you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_WORKING_WITH_1">
			<Text>Such a pleasure having you here again. Shall we do the usual?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_WORKING_WITH_2">
			<Text>Oh my dearest... Friend, I was wondering when you would show up again. Care to accompany me to some more private quarters?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_COOP_WAR_1">
			<Text>Soon enough we won't have to worry about {1_ThirdPlayerName:textkey}. Then we'll have more time for us...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_COOP_WAR_2">
			<Text>I hope you're looking forward to the downfall of {1_ThirdPlayerName:textkey} as much as I am. I'll be sure to show my full appreciation for your actions once this is done.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_COOP_WAR_3">
			<Text>I'm eager to take down {1_ThirdPlayerName:textkey} by your side. Hopefully it won't be the last time we... Work together.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>I've heard about the war you're waging and I must say there is room for improval. Maybe I could personally teach you...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>Oh my, you're here! I've been watching your battles closely, such dazzling heroism...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>Word has reached Assyria of your conquests. I hope you are willing to show me a bit of that ferocious might...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>I sure wish that you aren't overcompensating for something with that army near my borders, I was hoping we could have some fun later.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>You have quite a large empire there; do you also possess an army large enough to protect it? I wonder what else do you have that is...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>Hmm mmh, quite a large empire you have there. Is that just to impress me?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>You know, there are many better things to spend gold on than lands. And they can still involve me, if so you wish...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>I see you like to ostent your wealth by purchasing lands near me. Buying me gifts would do that job even better, you know.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>You've done a great job with your military. I've met a couple of your soldiers earlier this week. Very, very impressive...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_ECONOMY_1">
			<Text>I have heard of the wealth that flows from your empire. I hope you enjoy my company enough to spend some of it on me...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_FEW_CITIES_1">
			<Text>For the ruler of such an small nation, you sure are quite something... Need help enlarging it?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_SMALL_ARMY_1">
			<Text>Hmm, you sure must be so full of yourself to think that you dont require an actual army. But looking at you again... That's somewhat justifiable.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_IS_WARMONGER_1">
			<Text>I have heards the rumors of your warmongering, and I might just have a good use to such savagery... If you are willing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_TOO_SOON_FOR_DOF_1">
			<Text>I'm very happy to do this casually, but it's too soon for us to be committing ourselves like that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOF_AI_DENOUNCE_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>{1_CivName} has insulted me dearly. As my... Personal friend, I was hoping you would show some support for me against such a brute empire, and jointly denounce them?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOF_NOT_HONORED_1">
			<Text>Pathetic, so you are on their side? Go find a harlot from that nation to be with then.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOF_NOT_HONORED_2">
			<Text>So much for a lover these days. If you won't help me, I'll go find someone who will.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DENOUNCING_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>Sorry honey, I'm afraid I don't like you that much anymore.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DENOUNCING_FRIEND_2">
			<Text>I'll treasure our memories, but all things must pass... Let me give you one last goodbye. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>Oh, so that's how it is, huh? I know you'll come crawling back to me soon enough, anyways. And I might just say no, too...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_2">
			<Text>Playing difficult with me, huh? Don't worry, I'll get you eventually.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DOFED_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>I've heard that you've become friends with {1_CivName}. I'm quite friends with {1_CivName} too... Maybe we should celebrate together?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DOFED_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>So you're getting friendly with {1_CivName}, huh? Those bastards don't deserve you, and I'm sure you'll realize this as so I have.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DENOUNCED_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>How come you dislike {1_CivName}? They're so adorable and cute and handsome and... Oh my...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DENOUNCED_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>I must thank you for denouncing {1_CivName} too, and show how much I appreciate what you did.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DOF_SO_AI_DOF_1">
			<Text>So, you trust {1_CivName}? Well, I trust your judgement then, and shall settle any disputes I have with them as well.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DENOUNCE_SO_AI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>I too dislike the brutes who call themselves {1_CivName}, they're so crude. Perhaps the combination of our denouncements will teach them a lesson.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DOF_SO_AI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>I won't stand idle while you insult my friends at {1_CivName}. And to think that we could have had something together...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DENOUNCE_SO_AI_DOF_1">
			<Text>I'll be sure to visit the leader of {1_CivName} now that I know you two have broken relations. Thanks!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT Diplo Text -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I sure wish that you aren't overcompensating for something with that army near my borders, I was hoping we could have some fun later.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Is that army near my borders there to impress me? You don't need to do that with me, sweetie...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_2">
			<Text>I sure wish that you aren't overcompensating for something with that army near my borders, I was hoping we could have some fun later.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_KILLED_PROTECTED_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>You lied to me! I had dear friends in {@1_MinorCivName}, and I'll let the whole world know what you did here!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_PROTECTED_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>Stop attacking {@1_MinorCivName}, silly, they are under my protection. You don't want to annoy me, do you?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>What do you have against me? Stop expanding into my lands!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_EXPANSION_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Why do you insist on expanding onto my lands? I could've just given them to you instead, you know. But in exchange of some favours, of course...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_EXPANSION_WARNING_2">
			<Text>If you keep expanding into lands I consider mine, it might ruin your chances with me, you know. You don't want that, do you?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_EXPANSION_WARNING_3">
			<Text>I'm happy to share many things with those I like, but if you keep taking them by force I might just stop liking you too.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_EXPANSION_WARNING_4">
			<Text>I know that expanding is fun, but can't you do it somewhere else? Why do you have to annoy me so?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_EXPANSION_BROKEN_PROMISE_1">
			<Text>You promised me to stop expanding into Assyria! I do not take so kindly on broken promises... From others to me, of course, haha.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PLOT_BUYING_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>You know, there are many better things to spend gold on than lands. And they can still involve me, if so you wish... So could you please stop that?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PLOT_BUYING_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I see you like to ostent your wealth by purchasing lands near me. Can you stop that? Buying me gifts would be better, you know.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PLOT_BUYING_BROKEN_PROMISE_1">
			<Text>You promised me to stop expanding into Assyria! I do not take so kindly on broken promises... From others to me, of course, haha.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PLOT_BUYING_BROKEN_PROMISE_2">
			<Text>I am very disappointed that you lied to me like that. Do you not like me at all?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WORK_WITH_US_1">
			<Text>We should probably announce our relationship to the world. They are beggining to catch up on us!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WORK_WITH_US_2">
			<Text>Shall we tell the world of our... Friendship? Haha.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>We should probably announce our relationship to the world. They are beggining to catch up on us!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_2">
			<Text>Shall we tell the world of our... Friendship? Haha.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>I tire of the simplicity of our previous arrangement. Shall we make things more... Interesting?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DENOUNCE_2">
			<Text>How about we spice up our relations?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_COOP_WAR_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>{1_PlayerName:textkey} annoys me greatly. Would you be a good friend and declare war on them with me? Rest assured I won't forget if you decide to help me, and reward you... Appropriately.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_COOP_WAR_REQUEST_2">
			<Text>I've tried enjoying {1_PlayerName:textkey} company, but some people just can't be pleased! Would you be willing to aid me in teaching him a lesson?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_COOP_WAR_TIME_1">
			<Text>It's time! Together we will teach {1_PlayerName:textkey} a lesson that cannot not be forgotten. I will look forward to fighting... And camping along your side.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_NOW_UNFORGIVABLE_1">
			<Text>I have never met a person I could not forgive or like. Now I just might have...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_NOW_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>I'm sorry. The circumstances force me to treat you as an enemy. Hopefully that wont last, right sweety?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_COMPLIMENT_1">
			<Text>I want you to know how much I enjoy your company. So hard it is to find one like you!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_BOOT_KISSING_1">
			<Text>Oh great one, it's clear to all that you are a wise and mighty ruler. And oh, so great you are indeed...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_BOOT_KISSING_2">
			<Text>I've heard of other leaders how much they fear you. I agree with them, but I don't have to fear you, right honey?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WARMONGER_1">
			<Text>Your highly aggressive behavior with other nations has not gone unnoticed. I wonder if you are like that... everywhere... ?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WARMONGER_2">
			<Text>It's clear you're a fairly uncivilized brute. Thankfully, I have a use for those, if you are willing...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WARMONGER_3">
			<Text>Your warmongering is a popular topic these days. Such an energetic ruler, you are...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WARMONGER_4">
			<Text>You're starting to attract quite a bit of attention. That can be a good or bad thing...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_MINOR_CIV_COMPETITION_1">
			<Text>I've noticed your relationship with {1_MinorCivName:textkey}. That's nice and all, but they are mine. I suggest you keep out of this, and I might even award you plentifully for it...</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Insults-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_INSULT_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_1">
			<Text>Hey, who told you could get up here? I was going to talk with you downstairs, where the peasants stay!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_INSULT_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_2">
			<Text>Sorry, I was taking a look at the map and noticed that you surprisingly still exists! How odd.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_INSULT_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_3">
			<Text>Oh look, it's my favorite City-state! Don't worry, I take care of my tributaries very, very well...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_INSULT_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_4">
			<Text>Ah, it's you. My apologies. Sometimes I get you mixed up with the barbarians I like to... Appease, from time to time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_INSULT_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>Please take better care of your soldiers. They don't look that good when coming here anymore. Oh, why they come here at all? I, uh, nothing!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_INSULT_BULLY_1">
			<Text>A rude bully such as yourself has no business ruling a civilization. I do might just have the right job for you, though...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_INSULT_UNHAPPINESS_1">
			<Text>I can hear your people wailing in sorrow all the way over in my empire. I was even tempted to go there myself to allay them for a few minutes...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_INSULT_UNHAPPINESS_2">
			<Text>With people so unhappy it's a shock to me that they'd keep you around as their leader... Do you not know how to please them?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_INSULT_CITIES_1">
			<Text>Having such a small empire, I do hope that's not a reflection of your... Oh, nevermind.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_INSULT_POPULATION_1">
			<Text>Travelers have told us that your empire's economy is in pretty sad shape. If you beg I might give you a hand. More than a hand, actually...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_INSULT_CULTURE_1">
			<Text>You are so crude, one who does not even know how to court women such as myself. Oh, but I'll sure help you along.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Public Declarations-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DECLARATION_PROTECT_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} announces to the world that it is now protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}. Attacking the City-State will greatly damage relations and may lead to war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DECLARATION_ABANDON_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} has taken back its guarantee of protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human is asking the AI for something-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_REPEAT_NO_1">
			<Text>Sorry, this is off-limits. Unless you want to do me some very specific favors...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DONT_SETTLE_YES_1">
			<Text>Of course! Anything for you, after all... Heh...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DONT_SETTLE_NO_1">
			<Text>Get over yourself, sweetie. The land belongs to who settles it first.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WORK_WITH_US_YES_1">
			<Text>Ohhh, you fancy me huh? Very well, I'll play along.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WORK_WITH_US_YES_2">
			<Text>Oh of course I accept it, silly!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WORK_WITH_US_YES_3">
			<Text>I am happy to accept, and I am extremely happy of what is to come.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DECLINE_1">
			<Text>I can't do that now. Maybe later; maybe after a few drinks with you... Who knows?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DECLINE_2">
			<Text>Sorry, but I'll not sell myself short like that. You'll have to work to get this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DECLINE_3">
			<Text>This arrangement does not interest me right now. Or maybe I just need to be courted a little bit more...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_COOP_WAR_YES_1">
			<Text>How intriguing... To wage war by your side and risk having our sweaty bodies stumble together on the battlefield... Oh yes, yes!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_COOP_WAR_SOON_1">
			<Text>Give me 10 turns to asseble the Assyrians; the best things in life take time, you know... I will come to you again when I am ready!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DEMAND_YES_1">
			<Text>Oh sweetie, you should leave that kind of talk on the bedroom! But very well, I shall comply.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_WEAK_1">
			<Text>Please. I can give this to you out of pity, if you beg enough.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>You dare insult me in such a manner? If you want it so much, come and take it. I'll be eagerly waiting in my bedroom...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_MUCH_1">
			<Text>No. I still have some semblant of dignity, even if you pig don't realize it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_SOON_2">
			<Text>This again? I won't give in so easily to you... But I sure am tempted...</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Responses to player -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HOSTILE_WE_BULLIED_MINOR_BAD_1">
			<Text>Let's see how that ends up for you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HOSTILE_WE_BULLIED_MINOR_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Hmm mhm, good boy.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WE_BULLIED_MINOR_BAD_1">
			<Text>Don't get so upset over it, I'm sure we can figure something out together.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_BULLIED_MINOR_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Good, I'll be watching you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_TRADE_CANT_MATCH_OFFER_1">
			<Text>I'm afraid I just don't have enough to give! Or maybe we could...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_STOP_DIGGINGX_1">
			<Text>I've noticed that you've been looking for cultural artifacts within our borders. I had enough people digging trough my trash in the past, could you just stop?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_STOP_DIGGING_DISAGREE_1">
			<Text>Sorry, our plans are too important to be stopped over a trinket.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_STOP_DIGGING_AGREE_1">
			<Text>Very well sweetie, I'll stop digging through your stuff.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_HUMAN_STOP_DIGGING_BAD_1">
			<Text>Oh boy, do I have to escalate this? You might just get hurt, honey.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_HUMAN_STOP_DIGGING_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Thank you for understanding. I knew I could count on you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DIPLO_DISCUSS_DONT_STOP_DIGGING">
			<Text>You can't tell me what to do, sweetie.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DIPLO_DISCUSS_STOP_DIGGING">
			<Text>I meant no offense by doing that. I' sorry, I can make up for it!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_AI_BY_FREEDOM_1">
			<Text>My people have true freedom, and yet you manage to corrupt them with your messages of so called "liberty" and "equality"! They'll sure come to their senses soon, I'm sure of it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_AI_BY_ORDER_1">
			<Text>You incite revolution in our lands, risking the true Order I've fought so hard to achieve in my empire. How many will have to die until this revolutionary spirit is placated?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_AI_BY_AUTOCRACY_1">
			<Text>How you managed to make my people willingly wish to forgo their freedom is beyond me, but I'll not give in to your Autocratic ways.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_HUMAN_BY_FREEDOM_1">
			<Text>Your citizens clamor for liberties. How can a ruler hate his people so much as to deprive them of freedom?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_HUMAN_BY_ORDER_1">
			<Text>The oppressed of your land are unhappy. Do you have no love for your subjects? How can you allow them to live such terrible lives in pain?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_HUMAN_BY_AUTOCRACY_1">
			<Text>Your people claim for a ruler who loves them enough to be strong and do what must be done. Maybe I'll give one to them, if you resist in your backward ways.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_SWITCHED_TO_FREEDOM_1">
			<Text>I greet you in joining us in our quest for Freedom. Freedom is the aspect of life I hold most dear; specially freedom to love!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_SWITCHED_TO_ORDER_1">
			<Text>I welcome you to the path of Order. All we have was made to be shared; including love!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_SWITCHED_TO_AUTOCRACY_1">
			<Text>I hail you for choosing the path of Autocracy. Only we, with our love for our peoples, can steer them in the right direction.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_INFLUENTIAL_ON_HUMAN_1">
			<Text>I am glad to see that sales of our souvenirs to tourists from your lands have reached record levels. The amazing works of our civilization are truly inspiring!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Deal Offers and related-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_LETS_HEAR_IT_1">
			<Text>I'm all ears!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_LETS_HEAR_IT_2">
			<Text>Tell me your deepest wishes...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PEACE_OFFER_1">
			<Text>Oh sweetie, shouldn't we finish this war already? I'm missing those old days...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PEACE_OFFER_2">
			<Text>Please, let's finish off here. I've been way too long without you around now.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PEACE_OFFER_3">
			<Text>Why don't we both just call our armies back and celebrate the return of peace together? What else could you want?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DEMAND_1">
			<Text>I want something you possess. And when I want something, I take it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_REQUEST_ITEM_1">
			<Text>I ask for a gift. Don't you think I deserve one, sweetie?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_OPEN_BORDERS_EXCHANGE_1">
			<Text>Let's open our borders for eachother, and I'll sure retribute with a somewhat similar favor...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_OPEN_BORDERS_OFFER_1">
			<Text>How about in exchange of open borders, I open something else for you... ?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PLAN_RESEARCH_AGREEMENT_1">
			<Text>How about we allow our scholars to participate in a Research Agreement? Doing so would require each of us to spend 150 [ICON_GOLD]. What do you think?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE](Agreeing will not form a Research Agreement yet)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESEARCH_AGREEMENT_OFFER_1">
			<Text>A Research Agreement would strengthen the relations between our two peoples, don't you think sweetie? And it's not like we have anything to hide after all that...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RENEW_DEAL_1">
			<Text>Shall we renew this deal? I can personally give a little bit more from my side than the last time, if that's necessary...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WANT_MORE_RENEW_DEAL_1">
			<Text>This deal was... Very good then, but my tastes have grown far and wide since then. Shall we renegotiate?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_LUXURY_TRADE_1">
			<Text>This deal would bring great benefit to both our nations, and beyond the economic, to you personally too...</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- AI Attacked by another player -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>Oh, I see you have balls! Too bad you're using them wrongly...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>You are an uncivilized brute. Luckily, I have use for those in my bedchamber.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_WEAK_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>I'm a little bit tired of all that... But okay, assemble my men for combat.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_WEAK_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>Mmh hmm, you see me weak and powerless and decide to take me by force? I like where this is going...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_STRONG_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>Do you truly think you're up for this challenge? Very well then, I too love playing games, and I know just what to do with you once you lose...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_STRONG_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>A bit precocious, are you? Hope that won't be a problem for me once I have you captured...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>Oh, so cute, you want to take me by force! Alright, I'll play my part then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_EXCITED_2">
			<Text>Oh, so cute, you want to take me by force! This only makes me desire you more...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_EXCITED_3">
			<Text>How exciting! I'll have to order my men not to kill you, this give me some very fun ideas...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_WEAK_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>I'm a little bit tired of all that... But okay, assemble my men for combat.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_STRONG_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>Oh, you want to prove your worth and take me by force? That's so cute of you! Very well then, I'll play my part.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_SAD_1">
			<Text>You wish to take me by force? Oh sweetie, I was already yours. But oh well, if I must fight...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_SAD_2">
			<Text>Why must you hurt my feeling so? Do you not like me at all?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_SAD_3">
			<Text>You made a mistake here. Not because I can defeat you; but because I didn't want to.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_SAD_4">
			<Text>Oh, so cute, you want to take me by force! This only makes me desire you more...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_BETRAYED_1">
			<Text>Oh, so cute, you want to take me by force! Alright, I'll play my part then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_BETRAYED_2">
			<Text>Oh, so cute, you want to take me by force! This only makes me desire you more...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_ATTACKED_MILITARY_PROMISE_BROKEN_1">
			<Text>You had promised me! How dare you lie to me in such manner? On the other hand, this only makes me desire you more...</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- AI Declaring War-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOW_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_1">
			<Text>I had fun with you so far. Now let's see who stays on top!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOW_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_2">
			<Text>I'm coming for you sweetie. Don't make me wait too long!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOW_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_3">
			<Text>I desire you sweetie, and what I desire, I have!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOW_LAND_1">
			<Text>I've grown quite fond of some men living on your land. I wish to take them onto my realm now.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_1">
			<Text>Don't worry sweetie, nothing personal, it's just that you're a stepping stone for world conquest! I'll make up for it once we're done here.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_1">
			<Text>Let's see who stays on top now!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_2">
			<Text>I'm coming for you sweetie. Don't make me wait too long, I want you right here!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOW_DESPERATE_1">
			<Text>You seem to be getting a little too big for me to take on, so I must act while I'm still on top. I did say JUST a little to big for me...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOW_BETRAYAL_1">
			<Text>I had fun with you so far. Now let's see who stays on top!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOW_BETRAYAL_2">
			<Text>Keep your friends close, and your enemies closer. Sorry I had to lie to you so much, but do know that I enjoyed at least SOME of it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_DOW_WEAK_BETRAYAL_1">
			<Text>You seem to be getting a little too big for me to take on, so I must act while I'm still on top. I did say JUST a little to big for me...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WAR_DEMAND_REFUSED_1">
			<Text>And so I take it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a human peace offer-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PEACE_WHAT_WILL_HUMAN_OFFER_1">
			<Text>Tell me your desires!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_PEACE_WHAT_WILL_HUMAN_OFFER_2">
			<Text>Tell what you wish of me...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>Come on sweetie, at least try to keep up with me!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_NO_PEACE_2">
			<Text>We're still having fun here, cutie.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>Are you trying to tell me that you can only last THAT long?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_2">
			<Text>I really thought you could last longer than this...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_3">
			<Text>Am I misremembering, or did you use to last longer than this?.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a discussion mode topics-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_RESPONSE_PLEASED_1">
			<Text>How lovely.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_RESPONSE_PLEASED_2">
			<Text>Thank you, dearie.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_RESPONSE_PLEASED_3">
			<Text>This pleases me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_RESPONSE_PLEASED_4">
			<Text>Very good!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_RESPONSE_THANKFUL_1">
			<Text>You have my thanks and appreciation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_RESPONSE_THANKFUL_2">
			<Text>Thank you. I'm sure I can work out on a reward for you...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_RESPONSE_THANKFUL_3">
			<Text>I'll remember your kindness to me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_RESPONSE_DISAPPOINTED_1">
			<Text>If that's your desire, there's nothing I can do about it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_RESPONSE_DISAPPOINTED_2">
			<Text>I am disappointed in you. And in me, I thought myself to be more seductive than this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_RESPONSE_DISAPPOINTED_3">
			<Text>That is disappointing. I was looking forward to arriving on an agreement with you...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_SO_BE_IT_1">
			<Text>As it must be.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_SO_BE_IT_2">
			<Text>I won't hold a grudge due to this, but things might get kinky later.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_SO_BE_IT_3">
			<Text>Hmm mmh.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RETURNED_CIVILIAN_1">
			<Text>Thank you for freeing my people. I can't imagine how it must be to be held captive by such savage brutes and... Hmmm, this gives me ideas...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_CULTURE_BOMBED_1">
			<Text>How dare you? One thing is to take ME, another entirely to fake FROM me!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_CULTURE_BOMBED_2">
			<Text>That's it, you really outdid yourself now. Don't expect much from me now.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_BAD_1">
			<Text>Well, at least you're honest. I like that! Meet me again once this is over.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_GOOD_1">
			<Text>I hope that's true, sweetie.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_BAD_1">
			<Text>Well, at least you're honest. I like that! Meet me again once this is over.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_GOOD_1">
			<Text>I hope that's true, sweetie.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HOSTILE_WE_ATTACKED_MINOR_BAD_1">
			<Text>We'll see how that goes.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HOSTILE_WE_ATTACKED_MINOR_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Right!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WE_ATTACKED_MINOR_BAD_1">
			<Text>I remain confident in my decision.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_RESPONSE_BAD_1">
			<Text>So sad that it had to come to this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- DIPLOMACY: BWN Vanilla -->
		<!-- Statements to player -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HOSTILE_WE_ATTACKED_YOUR_MINOR_1">
			<Text>I thought you might like to know that I've launched an invasion of one of your little pet states, {@1_MinorCivName}. Gonna do something about it, sweetie?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HOSTILE_WE_ATTACKED_YOUR_MINOR_2">
			<Text>Oops, it seems I've attacked your little friend {@1_MinorCivName}. Gonna do something about it, sweetie?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WE_ATTACKED_YOUR_MINOR_1">
			<Text>I might have attacked a city-state under your protection, {@1_MinorCivName}... I'm sorry for this transgression, but the heart desires what the heart desires! I'll surely make it up to you sometime.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_EMBASSY_EXCHANGE_1">
			<Text>We should consider exchanging embassies, which would allow us to meet more often and get to know eachother well...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_EMBASSY_OFFER_1">
			<Text>I'd very much like to set up an embassy in your capital. We should be able to meet more often there...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_BULLIED_PROTECTED_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>Your bullying of {@1_MinorCivName} is intolerable. Stop stealing from city-states under my protection!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HOSTILE_WE_BULLIED_YOUR_MINOR_1">
			<Text>Your little friend {@1_MinorCivName} is so easy to push around. They gave in to our tribute demands, but don't worry, we also did plenty more fun things...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WE_BULLIED_YOUR_MINOR_1">
			<Text>I had to demand tribute from {@1_MinorCivName}, which is under your protection. Hopefully you put my needs above theirs, right sweetie?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_CAUGHT_YOUR_SPY_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>I caught one of your spies today. What I wonder the most is why he was attempting to steal such a basic technology, but then I realized that it's your empire we're talking about!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_CAUGHT_YOUR_SPY_FRIENDLY_1">
			<Text>I caught one of your spies today. Such a cute little thing, we had much fun together. Still, don't do it again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_CAUGHT_YOUR_SPY_GOOD_1">
			<Text>I'm glad you're reasonable. I can make up to it in other ways, you know.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_CAUGHT_YOUR_SPY_BAD_1">
			<Text>Hah, so feisty! I'll be eagerly waiting for your next spy then... Or maybe you can come yourself?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_STOP_SPYING_YES_1">
			<Text>You don't like my spies? But I sent them specially for your enjoyment... Very well then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_STOP_SPYING_NO_1">
			<Text>Hmm mmh, I stop sending my spies to your empire the day you stop being so annoying. How about that?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_WARNED_ABOUT_INTRIGUE_1">
			<Text>Thank you for bringing this {@1_CivAdjective} plot to my attention. Follow me and allow me to properly reward you...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_DECEPTION_1">
			<Text>My spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} is plotting against you, sweetie. I hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_ARMY_SNEAK_ATTACK_KNOWN_CITY_1">
			<Text>My spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} is currently marching an army to sneak attack your city of {2_CityName}, sweetie. I hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_ARMY_SNEAK_ATTACK_UNKNOWN_CITY_1">
			<Text>My spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} is currently marching an army your way in a sneak attack, sweetie. I hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_AMPHIBIOUS_SNEAK_ATTACK_KNOWN_CITY_1">
			<Text>My spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} embarked an army with naval escorts to sneak attack your city of {2_CityName}, sweetie. I hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_AMPHIBIOUS_SNEAK_ATTACK_UNKNOWN_CITY_1">
			<Text>My spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} embarked an army with naval escorts in a sneak attack against your civilization, sweetie. I hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_KILLED_YOUR_SPY_1">
			<Text>We captured your spy as it was trying to steal from us. I'll be keeping him on my dungeon, if you don't mind...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_KILLED_MY_SPY_1">
			<Text>I do regret my misdeeds. I did not expect my agent to be killed. Please, accept my apologies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_CONFRONT_YOU_KILLED_MY_SPY_1">
			<Text>Hey sweetie. Are you here about that little spying thing? You shouldn't worry about that...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_SUSPECT_YOU_OF_SPYING_1">
			<Text>Oh sweetie, don't be such a creep. I know that you are spying on me, even though you could very well come here and see it all for yourself...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_STOP_CONVERSIONS_1">
			<Text>You need to stop converting my followers to your religion. If I wanted that, I'd do it myself.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_HUMAN_KILLED_MY_SPY_UNFORGIVEN_1">
			<Text>You... You can't forgive me? Oh my, am I getting worse at this?!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_HUMAN_KILLED_MY_SPY_FORGIVEN_1">
			<Text>Thank you for understanding, you silly. Now come here.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_STOP_CONVERSIONS_GOOD_1">
			<Text>I'm glad you agreed to end this proselytizing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_STOP_CONVERSIONS_BAD_1">
			<Text>Your religious fervor is truly unsettling. But as long as it doesn't impact your... Performance...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_HUMAN_STOP_CONVERSIONS_AGREE_1">
			<Text>I am happy to oblige, I'll recall back my missionaries right away. I missed them here anyway...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_RESPONSE_HUMAN_STOP_CONVERSIONS_DISAGREE_1">
			<Text>No, I had a... Falling out, let's call it that, with one of those missionaries and don't want him back here. They need to continue!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_WILL_ACCEPT_SURRENDER_1">
			<Text>We can make a deal now, I keep you in power and... You give yourself unconditionally to me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_GREETING_WILL_ACCEPT_SURRENDER_2">
			<Text>Oh sweetie, let me finish this war already! I miss having you here...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WE_LIKE_HUMAN_PROPOSAL_1">
			<Text>What an explendid proposal to the {1_LeagueName}.  I can see myself enjoying working with you thoroughly.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WE_LIKE_HUMAN_PROPOSAL_2">
			<Text>Your proposal to the {1_LeagueName} suits my interests quite nicely.  I wonder... Do I suit yours?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_WE_DISLIKE_HUMAN_PROPOSAL_1">
			<Text>Your proposal to the {1_LeagueName} is a blatant attack on my interests.  There are better places to treat me roughly...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_SUPPORTED_OUR_PROPOSAL_1">
			<Text>Thanks to your personal help, my recent proposal to the {1_LeagueName} was passed.  What about I return the favor right now...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_SUPPORTED_OUR_PROPOSAL_2">
			<Text>My proposal to the {1_LeagueName} succeeded, with your support.  I'll be sure visiting your palace soon to thank you...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_FOILED_OUR_PROPOSAL_1">
			<Text>You played vital part in the failure of my proposal to the {1_LeagueName}.  Do you not like me at all anymore?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_FOILED_OUR_PROPOSAL_2">
			<Text>My proposal to the {1_LeagueName} was defeated at your hands.  So rude, so rude.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TCM_SAMMURAMAT_HUMAN_SUPPORTED_OUR_HOSTING_1">
			<Text>Thank you for choosing me as leader of the World Congress.  I am sure to support you as well in the {1_LeagueName}.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>