<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!-- City names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_1">
			<Text>Arawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_2">
			<Text>Buka</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_3">
			<Text>Panguna</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_4">
			<Text>Buin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_5">
			<Text>Wakunai</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_6">
			<Text>Kara</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_7">
			<Text>Kokopau</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_8">
			<Text>Torokina</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_9">
			<Text>Lemankoa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_10">
			<Text>Tangari</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_11">
			<Text>Mosigo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_12">
			<Text>Tarlena</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_13">
			<Text>Kunapopo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_14">
			<Text>Orava</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_15">
			<Text>Hanahan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_16">
			<Text>Toimonapu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_17">
			<Text>Amun</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_18">
			<Text>Koripobi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_19">
			<Text>Siara</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_20">
			<Text>Isinai</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_21">
			<Text>Bogisage</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_22">
			<Text>Kupi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_23">
			<Text>Puto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_24">
			<Text>Kopikiri</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_25">
			<Text>Aropa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_26">
			<Text>Kunua</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_27">
			<Text>Ibu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_28">
			<Text>Taruba</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_29">
			<Text>Aku</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_30">
			<Text>Puputun</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_31">
			<Text>Vito</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_32">
			<Text>Taki</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_33">
			<Text>Motupena</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_34">
			<Text>Konga</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_35">
			<Text>Boku</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_36">
			<Text>Jaba</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_9">
			<Text>Musingku</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_8">
			<Text>Doaninoel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_7">
			<Text>Katua</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_6">
			<Text>Kurongku</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_5">
			<Text>Semoso</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_4">
			<Text>Hakena</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_3">
			<Text>Tsiamalili</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_2">
			<Text>Sarei</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_1">
			<Text>Momis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_0">
			<Text>Akoitai</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Bougainville -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE">
			<Text>Bougainville</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_SHORT">
			<Text>Bougainville</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILIZATION_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Bougainvillean</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Bougainville Island is the main island of the Autonomous Region of Bougainville of Papua New Guinea, also known as Bougainville Province. It formed the main landmass of the German Empire-associated North Solomons. It is the largest of the Solomon Islands archipelago, most of which, concentrated south and east, are politically independent as the Solomon Islands; from two of these in the close-knit Shortland Islands it is less than 9 km north or north-west to Bougainville; they are in turn about 30 km west of Choiseul, a settlement of which, Poroporo, faces Bougainville.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Bougainville was first settled some 28,000 years ago. Three to four thousand years ago, Austronesian people arrived, bringing with them domesticated pigs, chickens, dogs, and obsidian tools. The first European contact with Bougainville was in 1768, when the French explorer Louis Antoine de Bougainville arrived and named the main island for himself. British and American whaling ships visited the island for provisions, water and wood in the 19th century. The first on record was the Roscoe in 1822, and the last was Palmetto in 1881. The German Empire laid claim to Bougainville in 1899, annexing it into German New Guinea. Christian missionaries arrived on the island in 1902. During World War I, Australia occupied German New Guinea, including Bougainville. It became part of the Australian Territory of New Guinea under a League of Nations mandate in 1920. In 1942, during World War II, Japan invaded the island, but allied forces launched the Bougainville campaign to regain control of the island in 1943. Despite heavy bombardments, the Japanese garrisons remained on the island until 1945. Following the war, the Territory of New Guinea, including Bougainville, returned to Australian control. On 9 September 1975, the Parliament of Australia passed the Papua New Guinea Independence Act 1975. The Act set 16 September 1975 as date of independence and terminated all remaining sovereign and legislative powers of Australia over the territory. Bougainville was to become part of an independent Papua New Guinea. However, on 11 September 1975, in a failed bid for self-determination, Bougainville declared itself the Republic of the North Solomons. The republic failed to achieve any international recognition, and a settlement was reached in August 1976. Bougainville was then absorbed politically into Papua New Guinea with increased self-governance powers.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The discovery of vast copper ore deposits in the Crown Prince Range on Bougainville Island during the 1960s led to the establishment of the huge Bougainville Copper Mine by the Australian company Conzinc Rio Tinto. The Panguna mine began production in 1972 under the management of Bougainville Copper Ltd, with the government of Papua New Guinea as a 20% shareholder. At the time, the Panguna mine was the largest open cut mine in the world. It produced more than 45% of Papua New Guinea's national export revenue, and was, as such, vitally important to the economy. By late 1988 tensions over the mine had led to local violence. The government deployed the Royal Papua New Guinea Constabulary (RPNGC) Mobile Squads and elements of the Papua New Guinea Defence Force (PNGDF). Although initially restricted to the area around the mine site, the conflict subsequently intensified. Both sides reported abuses against the native population during fighting between government forces and the rebels of the Bougainville Revolutionary Army (BRA) and the conflict developed into a general separatist insurgency. The mine company closed the mine, and many non-Bougainvilleans left the island. Fighting continued for a year, during which widespread human rights violations were alleged to have occurred, including the burning of many villages. However, in early 1990 Papua New Guinea withdrew, leaving Bougainville in the control of the BRA. Despite agreeing to disarm and negotiate, Francis Ona, the leader of the BRA, unilaterally declared independence in May 1990. The PNG government subsequently imposed a blockade on Bougainville. The blockade would remain in effect until the ceasefire in 1994 (although it was informally continued for some parts of Bougainville until 1997). Ona subsequently set up the Bougainville Interim Government (BIG), appointing himself president. The former premier of the provincial government, Joseph Kabui, was appointed Vice-President. The military commander of the BRA was Sam Kauona, a former PNGDF officer. Yet the BIG had little power, and the island began to descend into disarray. The command structure set up by the BRA seldom had any real control over the various groups throughout the island that claimed to be part of the BRA, A number of raskol (criminal) gangs that were affiliated with the BRA, equipped largely with weapons salvaged from the fighting in World War II, terrorized villages, engaging in murder, rape and pillage. Bougainville split into several factions, as the conflict took on ethnic and separatist characteristics. The divisions in the conflict were largely drawn along clan lines. There were 70–80 minor tribal conflicts for BIG to deal with in addition to the blockade. As the BIG/BRA was dominated by the Nasioi clan, other islanders were suspicious of its goals, especially in north Bougainville. On the island of Buka, north of Bougainville, a local militia was formed which succeeded in driving out the BRA with help from Papuan troops. By the end of 1990, the PNGDF national forces controlled Buka, while the BRA controlled the remainder of Bougainville. In 1992–93, the PNGDF launched a number of unauthorised cross-border raids into the Solomon Islands in pursuit of supporters of the BRA. Relations with the Solomon Islands deteriorated, and on one occasion PNG forces clashed with Solomon Island police, exchanging fire. The PNGDF, in alliance with the resistance, reoccupied Arawa, the provincial capital, in February 1993. Papuan Foreign Minister Sir Julius Chan attempted to gather a peacekeeping force from the nations of the Pacific, but Wingti quashed the idea. He subsequently ordered the army to retake the Panguna mine, and was initially successful. However, his government was short-lived, and in August 1994 was replaced as Prime Minister by Julius Chan. The assault on Panguna subsequently failed.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Sandline affair began in March 1996, when the government of Papua New Guinea attempted to hire mercenaries from Sandline International, a London-based private military company, that in turn employed the South African military contractor Executive Outcomes. Chan decided that his best chance to recapture the Panguna mine was with the Sandline mercenaries, and a contract was signed in January 1997. However, news of his intention to hire mercenaries was leaked to the Australian press, and international condemnation followed. Although initially supportive, the commander of the PNGDF, Jerry Singirok, then opposed the plan, and ordered all the mercenaries to be detained on arrival. In the resulting saga Papua New Guinea came close to a military coup, with the parliament surrounded by demonstrators and many military personnel. The Australian government placed pressure on PNG to terminate the contract with Sandline, and intercepted the heavy equipment that was being flown-in for the mercenaries. Chan resigned and the mercenaries were removed from Papua New Guinean territory. Meanwhile, the conflict continued until 1997.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Since then a ceasefire has largely held on the island. Breaking with Ona, Kauona and Kabui entered into peace talks with the Skate government in Christchurch, New Zealand, which culminated in the signing of the Lincoln Agreement in January 1998. Under the terms of the agreement, PNG began to withdraw its soldiers from the island, and steps were taken to disarm the BRA and BRF, while a multinational Peace Monitoring Group (PMG) under Australian leadership was deployed, replacing the TMG. Legislation to establish a Bougainville Reconciliation Government failed to win approval in the PNG Parliament in December 1998. A final peace agreement was reached in 2001, leading to a roadmap to the creation of an Autonomous Bougainville Government (ABG). Yet Ona refused to play any part in the peace process, and, with a small minority of fighters, broke away from the BRA. Throughout the decade, he continued to resist overtures to participate in the new government, occupying an area around the mine which remained a no-go zone and declaring himself 'king' of Bougainville before dying of malaria in 2005. Elections for the first ABG were held in May and June 2005 with Joseph Kabui elected president.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A condition of the peace agreement was that a referendum on Bougainville's political status would be held within twenty years, scheduled sometime between 2015 and 2020. In January 2016 the Autonomous Bougainville Government and Government of Papua New Guinea agreed to establish the Bougainville Referendum Commission. The Commission was tasked with making preparations for a vote on Bougainville's future political status in 2019. In late November and early December 2019, a non-binding referendum on independence was held with an overwhelming majority voting for independence.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Francis Ona -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GT_FRANCIS_ONA">
			<Text>Francis Ona</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>	
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Francis Ona was a Bougainville secessionist leader who led an uprising against the Government of Papua New Guinea as part of the Bougainville Civil War. He and his followers were concerned about the environmental and social effects of the operation of the Panguna mine by Bougainville Copper, a subsidiary of Rio Tinto Group. On 17 May 1990, Ona declared the independence of the Republic of Me'ekamui. It was not recognised internationally. In May 2004 Ona proclaimed himself "King of Me'ekamui." While resisting the peace process and 2005 elections, Ona mostly stayed in a safe haven, where his BRA forces controlled territory.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ona was at one time employed by Bougainville Copper at the mine, but he became increasingly critical of its operations' adverse effect on the environment and what he claimed was the low level of royalties paid the landowners. Most of the profits left Bougainville Island, but its society was disrupted by thousands of workers from Papua New Guinea, as well as Australians. From the mid-1980s, Ona and others challenged the leadership of the Panguna Landowners Association (PLA), claiming that they were not representing the interests of all the traditional landowners.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]By early 1988, Ona and his associates, including his cousin Pepetua Serero, had formed the New PLA, supported by both mineworkers and the traditional opponents of the Panguna mine, Damien Dameng's Me'ekamui Pontuku Onoring. The New PLA made a number of demands, including monetary compensation for the impacts of the mine, a 50 per cent share of mine revenue to the landholders, and a transfer of ownership to Bougainville. The PNG Government set up an independent inquiry which dismissed the claims about the environmental impact but was critical of other parts of the mine's operation. In response, Ona established the Bougainville Revolutionary Army (BRA), which conducted numerous acts of sabotage against the mine including the destruction of the mine's power supply. The mine was closed by Bougainville Copper in May 1989. Ona rejected an initial compromise deal by Bougainville Copper and the PNG government.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ona became the acknowledged leader of the BRA after the death of Serero in 1989; Sam Kauona, a former soldier in the army, led military operations. The Papua New Guinea Government sent in the police and then the army under Jerry Singirok to quell the uprising, but they were unable to do so. The island was placed under a State of Emergency under the control of the PNG Police Commissioner. The number of complaints increased about human rights abuses by PNG forces, which initially strengthened support for the BRA.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In January 1990, Bougainville Copper announced that they were suspending operations at the mine. The PNG Government announced that they would withdraw troops and for international observers to verify the disarmament of the BRA. The police fled fearing for their lives in the absence of the army, and there was an attempted coup in Port Moresby over the deal.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In response to a blockade imposed by the PNG Government later in 1990, Ona said he was the head of the Bougainville Interim Government and declared independence for the island. The island descended into anarchy, as several armed factions and clans struggled for power; the PNG Government supported these militias. The BRA leaders fell out with Joseph Kabui, the Premier of Bougainville, who had previously been a supporter. A ceasefire was arranged in 1997 between new Prime Minister Bill Skate and Joseph Kabui, with a multi-national Peace Monitoring Group commencing operations on the island. Though Ona and the BRA controlled 90% of the island, his break with Kabui meant that the BRA representatives were not involved in the talks. Ona believed that the New Zealand-brokered peace talks were unwarranted outside interference with Bougainville governance, and did not participate.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ona was subsequently ignored in the creation of the Autonomous Bougainville Government. At this time Ona agreed with Noah Musingku to establish a funding source for Bougainville that would allow true sovereignty. This system was developed as the U-Vistract system, which sought to use the untapped natural resources of Bougainville to finance reconstruction. Ona remained isolated in the Panguna region, which BRA controlled for the next 16 years. The Bougainville conflict is estimated to have cost between 10,000 and 15,000 lives, mainly due to disease and starvation among the civilian residents. A tribal reconciliation process started in 2000 appears to have been successful. The PNG government promised in 2001 to hold a referendum on independence within the next ten to fifteen years. The referendum was held in 2019, and voters voted overwhelmingly for independence.=[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]On 17 May 2004, Ona declared himself "King of Bougainville" or Mekamui. He was crowned "King Francis Dominic Dateransy Domanaa, head of state of the Royal Kingdom of Me'ekamui". "Me'ekamui", meaning "holy" or "Holy Land", is an old tribal name for Bougainville. During elections for the Autonomous government in 2005, which he opposed, Ona came out of his safe haven into the public eye for the first time in 16 years. He declared that Bougainville was already independent and capable of running its own affairs. Perhaps as a result of Ona's continued influence in Bougainville, only 3% of the eligible voters participated in the May 2005 elections of the New Zealand-brokered Autonomous Government.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ona died on 24 July 2005 of malaria in his village. Ona was never captured and refused to participate in the peace process. His forces still controlled over half of the island.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_NAME">
			<Text>Francis Ona</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>King of Me'ekemaui</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Leader of the BRA</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_LIVED">
			<Text>1953 - July 2005</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_TEXT">
			<Text>A struggle awaits, King Francis Ona, feared leader and liberator of the Bougainville people! You led a revolt againt international and colonial oppressors that grew into an island-wide war for independence. While others viewed violence as immoral, you recongised that armed conflict was the only way to gain true freedom for the island. Against all the odds and a global coalition of enemies, your troops armed with makeshift rifles repelled their advances and defended the economoic wealth of the island. While ignored and refused a voice in the susequent peace process, your legacy was such that the island, years after your death and the establishment of the Kingdom, voted for complete independence. You became an icon, a role model, for liberation movements around the world. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Commander! While your people are unified in independence, foreign forces once again seek impose their dominion on Bougainville. Your holy kingdom grows ever weaker, as the great veterans of the conflict fade into obscurity. Every Bougainvillean looks to you, their King, to ensure that their independence is final. They look to you as you alone have the knowledge to outsmart the invaders. So, commander, will you rise to the occasion? Will you return to the holy kingdom? Will you build a civilization that will stand the test of Time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Coco rev -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_GT_COCONUT_REVOLUTION_SHORT">
			<Text>Coconut Revolution</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_GT_COCONUT_REVOLUTION">
			<Text>Cities will raise militias on mined resources if invaded, which ignore terrain penalties if raised during a [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] We Love the King Day. During war, receive the yields of mines of city states and allied cities nearest to your empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- MDF -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_GT_MEKEMAUI_DEFENCE_FORCE">
			<Text>Me'ekemaui Defence Force</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_GT_MEKEMAUI_DEFENCE_FORCE_TEXT">
			<Text>The Bougainville Revolutionary Army (BRA) was a secessionist group formed in 1988 by Bougainvilleans seeking independence from Papua New Guinea (PNG). The leader of the BRA was Francis Ona who led the BRA against the Papua New Guinea Defence Force during the violent 10 year conflict. Not all BRA members agreed to the Peace Treaty and boycotted it, and have held out in an official no-go zone, creating the Meekamui Defence Force to prtoect important areas such as the Pangua Mine, which is currently commanded by Moses Pepino. The BRA is no longer actively engaged in fighting, although some of its leaders are involved in the autonomous goverment established after the ceasefire. The MDF regards itself as the armed forces of the Kingdom of Meekemaui, officially known as the Meekemaui Government of Unity.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_GT_MEKEMAUI_DEFENCE_FORCE_HELP">
			<Text>Replaces the Marine. More expensive to train, and unlocked earlier at Radio. May attack twice while in Jungle. +50% attacking Strength against units recruited with Gold, -50% attacking strength outside friendly territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_GT_MEKEMAUI_DEFENCE_FORCE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>MDF units are crucial in keeping hold of your friendly territory when threatened, especially when up against a more powerful enemy. Tech need not be an obstacle as they are unlocked at Radio, allowing for a sizaeble force of Defence Forces to fight off invaders in jungle.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Promotions -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_GT_MEEKEMAUI">
			<Text>Defenders of the Holy Kingdom</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_GT_MEEKEMAUI_HELP">
			<Text>+50% attacking Strength against units recruited with Gold, -50% Defensive strength outside friendly territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_GT_COCONUT_REVOLUTION">
			<Text>Coconut Revolutionaries</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_GT_COCONUT_REVOLUTION_HELP">
			<Text>Cities celebrating a [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] We Love the King Day will raise militias on mined resources if invaded by an enemy by sea, which ignore terrain penalties whilst undamaged.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_GT_ATTACKING_MERCENARY">
			<Text>No to Sandline International!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_GT_ATTACKING_MERCENARY_HELP">
			<Text>+50% attacking Strength against units recruited with Gold</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_GT_PURCHASED_WITH_GOLD">
			<Text>Mercenaries</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_GT_PURCHASED_WITH_GOLD_HELP">
			<Text>Unit recruited with [ICON_GOLD] Gold</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Buildings-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GT_U_VISTRACT">
			<Text>U-Vistract</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GT_U_VISTRACT_HELP">
			<Text>Replaces the Stock Exchange. Recieve a free U-Vistract upon improving Copper, once per era. While a Great Merchant is in the territory of City-States or another civilization, production from worked mines and tourism is converted into border culture and WLKTD length is doubled. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GT_U_VISTRACT_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Useful for reinvigorating resistance against an invasion or for profiting off of larger civilizations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GT_U_VISTRACT_TOOLTIP">
			<Text>While a Great Merchant is in the territory of City-States or another civilization, production from worked mines and tourism is converted into border culture and WLKTD length is doubled.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GT_U_VISTRACT_TEXT">
			<Text>The U-Vistract is a financial enterprise created by the leadership of the Bougainville Revolutionary Army as a means to generate an outside source of income for the newly self-declared independent nation, particularly as the Papuan government had blockaded major ports on the island and the BRA had been excluded from peace talks. Functionally a pyramid scheme, it offered investors across Melanesia and Australia the chance to access Bougainville's rich natural resources, primarily copper and rare earth metals. After the peace accords in 1998 and the death of Ona in 2005, the scheme was banned outside of the island and evolved to become the financial arm of the Mekemaui kingdom, proclaimed by Ona in 2004, who to this day roughly control a third of the island, centered at the disused Pangara copper mine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GT_UVISTRACT_TOURISM">
			<Text>Bougainville: U-Vistract Tourism 2 Culture</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GT_UVISTRACT_TOURISM_HELP">
			<Text>While a Great Merchant is in the territory of City-States or another civilization, worked mines convert tourism to border culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GT_UVISTRACT_WLTKD">
			<Text>Bougainville: U-Vistract WLTKD Doubled</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GT_UVISTRACT_WLTKD_HELP">
			<Text>While a Great Merchant is in the territory of City-States or another civilization, WLKTD length is doubled.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GT_COCONUT_REVOLUTION">
			<Text>Bougainville: Coconut Revolution</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GT_COCONUT_REVOLUTION_HELP">
			<Text>During war, receive the yields of mines of city states and allied cities nearest to your empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Responses-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Who are you? Are you here to invest in our vast natural wealth? Or are you here on behalf on the Papuans? Speak, friend, I do not care for long negotiations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>We are at peace, it seems. You may govern in the cities and towns, but we will always hold supremacy among the villages and vasts forests of this place. Independence is not a cause I can be persuaded out of.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>Another foreigner looking for colonial spoils! I will defend this independent holy land to the death. Lift a finger on the island and it will be chopped off.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>You look to me to be one of the only foreigners who understand my people's struggle. But this understanding need not be invisible. Would you accept a common declaration of friendship?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>Among all the vile creatures that call themselves leaders, you are without a doubt the ugliest. My loyalists will make short work of you.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_DENOUNCE_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>You appeared to me as a friend. But of course, that was only a mask for your true desires, as it always is.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>I am a man of peace. But I see no way that peace can be achieved without the ritual of war. For independence!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GT_FRANCIS_ONA_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>I don't see what you have to gain by denouncing our nation. It is a small nation, but if you insist it will make short work of you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Mod Support-->
		<!--Achievements-->
		<Replace Tag="TXT_KEY_TAB_AA_GT_HEADER">
			<Text>Grant's Achievements</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="TXT_KEY_TAB_AA_GT_DESC">
			<Text>All Achievements related to or added by Grant mods.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Boogie-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_NAME">
			<Text>Grant's Bougainville (Francis Ona)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_MODID">
			<Text>93a5089b-cccf-48de-b766-f753b3d62bac</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_AUTHORS">
			<Text>Grant</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Holy Kingdom of Solomon-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AA_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_VICTORY_HEADER">
			<Text>Holy Kingdom of Solomon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AA_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_VICTORY_TEXT">
			<Text>Beat the game on any victory setting as Francis Ona of Bougainville.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Sardine International-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AA_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_SPECIAL_HEADER">
			<Text>Sardine International</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AA_GT_BOUGAINVILLE_SPECIAL_TEXT">
			<Text>As King Francis Ona of Bougainville, destroy 10 or more embarked enemy units on sources of Fish.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>