<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by Tomatekh -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_FUJI_CULT_SM">
			<Text>Fujiko</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_FUJI_CULT_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>Fujiko, otherwise known as Fuji Shinko and Sengen Shinko, is the name given to a popular religion or cult that developed in the Azuchi-Momoyama and early Edo periods (late 1500s and 1600s) in eastern Japan, centred around the worship of Mount Fuji, Japan’s highest and most distinctive mountain. Although the mountain had been revered for some time previously, Fujiko proper was founded by Hasegawa Kakugyo (c. 1541-c. 1646), originally a Shugendo practitioner from far Kyushu. Fujiko practitioners, in a manner not dissimilar to the Ise pilgrims commonplace in Edo Japanese society, soon banded together into 'confraternities', assisting their members in climbing Mount Fuji, along with, presumably, distributing the other paraphernalia associated with Fujiko such as 'fusegi' ritual talismans.   Although the Fujiko themselves have largely disappeared, Japan is not without clues to their former glory: two Shinto sects that are directly descended from the Fujiko still exist and have about 150,000 followers between them; the town of Fuji-Yoshida, which largely developed around the Fujiko, is still the most popular gateway for modern-day mountain tourists; and, perhaps most intriguingly, various shrines around the Kanto region still maintain Fujizuka – tiny Mount Fujis, climbable in a few seconds by those looking for Fujiko-style salvation but unable to make it to the real peak.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_JODO_SHINSHU_SM">
			<Text>Jodo Shinshu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_JODO_SHINSHU_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>Jodo Shinshu, a Mahayana Buddhist sect founded by the monk Shinran in the early 1200s, is in some ways the polar opposite of the esoteric sects that were predominant in Japanese Buddhism up until the end of the Heian period (late 1100s). Unlike most other forms of Buddhism, Jodo Shinshu, and its parent sect Jodoshu, essentially recognise only one Buddha - Amida or Amitabha - and one religious practice - the repeated chanting of the nenbutsu, a short phrase translating as something like 'Hail Amida!'. Through this practice, Jodo adherents claim (according to Jodoshu, the link is direct, but for Jodo Shinshu, it is indirect and a sort of 'trust' in the power of Amida is more important than the actual chanting), it is possible to bypass the regular Buddhist cycle of reincarnation and be reborn in Amida's Pure Land, a separate realm to nirvana.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]These teachings were especially popular around the time when the sect was founded, as Buddhist theologians of the time - perhaps influenced by the widespread famine and political strife of 1200s Japan - believed that the Latter Days of the [Buddhist] Law had reached Japan, and that the 'regular' Buddhist cycle of reincarnation was becoming less reliable. Jodo Shinshu became even more appealing than regular Jodoshu to everyday Japanese of the time by abolishing many of the unpopular parts of the religion's code of conduct, including the need for celibacy. This new, popular Buddhism scared the political and religious establishment in Japan, and the Jodo Shinshu Patriarchs spent the next few centuries running around the country trying to keep one step ahead of the establishment, sometimes inspiring popular revolts (ikko-ikki) that in turn occasionally took control of significant-sized areas of the country, including what are now the modern cities of Osaka and Kanazawa. Although the independent Patriarchs suffered heavily under Oda Nobunaga, his successor Toyotomi Hideyoshi took a radically different approach, officially granting legitimacy to Jodo Shinshu. From there, the only way was up, and Shinran's easily accessible teachings are now the most widely practiced form of Japanese Buddhism.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_KAMUI_SM">
			<Text>Kamuism</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_KAMUI_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>'Kamuism' is the name given here to the traditional religion of Japan's indigenous Ainu people, usually associated with Hokkaido but now recognised as the original inhabitants of Japan as a whole. Ainu religion has a few similarities with Shinto, particularly the forms of it that existed prior to the arrival of Buddhism, in that it is strongly animist, believing that everything has a kamuy, a god or spirit. Kamuy can be local phenomena, tied to a local terrain feature or even a family, but can also be beings that watch over all Ainu lands, such as Ape-huci-kamuy, the Grandmother Goddess of the home. Kamuy worship leads to Ainu hunters traditionally thanking the spirits of the land after a successful hunt, in a manner sometimes also seen in Native American cultures, and occasionally, performing an elaborate ceremony involving raising and ultimately killing a bear or other large animal to 'send back' its spirit to the land of the gods - a practice which has, perhaps unfortunately, become the most well-known aspect of Ainu culture overseas.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_KOSHINTO_SM">
			<Text>Koshinto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_KOSHINTO_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>Koshinto, literally 'old Shinto', refers to the religious practices of pre-Buddhist Japan. As the advent of written records in Japan largely began after the arrival of Buddhism, little is known of Koshinto, but it appears that the Shinto concept of kami existed in Koshinto as well, along with that of 'mitama', a person's detachable soul or spirit. One of the earliest recorded ritual practices of Yayoi Japan was that of praying to, or making offerings to, the deity or deities of an area of land, as a way of praying for victory in a battle one will soon contest there. Perhaps the most famous and notable feature of ancient Shinto was its emphasis on the role of women as priests, or as envoys to the gods - most notably, the legendary Queen Himiko (c. 170-248), the existence of whom we only know about from Chinese records. As the arrival of Confucianism led to both China and Japan becoming solidly patriarchal, Himiko, as a female supreme ruler (early Japanese administration and religion were largely one and the same, as can be seen with the original Japanese word for 'governance' being cognate with that for 'festival'), was largely forgotten about, along with the rest of Koshinto. This only changed with the 1700s Kokugaku movement in Japan, wherein the old ways were once again celebrated as a uniquely Japanese tradition, contrasted with the 'newfangled impostor' of Chinese-derived tradition.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_NICHIREN_SM">
			<Text>Nichiren</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_NICHIREN_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>Nichiren Buddhism is a Mahayana sect founded in the 1200s by Nichiren, a priest from eastern Japan. Like Jodo Shinshu, another Buddhist sect founded at a similar time to Nichiren and which has taken a similar path through history, Nichiren Buddhism rejects most of the orthodox Buddhist canon, instead focusing on one part (the Lotus Sutra) and, largely, the teachings of Nichiren himself (the Gosho). Similarly, one chant (Namu Myoho Renge Kyo, 'Hail the Lotus Sutra!', predominates in Nichiren Buddhism. The sect is perhaps most notable for being possibly the most like a Western Abrahamic religion of any Japanese Buddhist sect, in that it has a history of denouncing, sometimes violently, other sects, and unlike other forms of Japanese Buddhism, encourages its followers to convert those adherents of other types of Buddhism to the Nichiren faith. This, combined with a greater emphasis on one's own 'power' compared to the focus on faith or trust of Jodo Shinshu and its kin, led to various conflicts with authorities, including urban rebellions in the 1500s and also more modern developments. The Nichiren canon is relatively egalitarian in relation to gender issues and the like, and Nichiren followers were active in pushes for equality and even socialism in the early 20th century, but those same teachings, at the same time, were also used as an excuse for ultranationalism - go figure.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_SHINGON_SM">
			<Text>Shingon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_SHINGON_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>Shingon is a sect of Japanese Buddhism, and the only one to be classed as Vajrayana rather than Mahayana. It was founded in the 800s by the legendary Japanese ascetic Kukai (Kobo Daishi) upon his return from China. (Along with Shingon and by extension Vajrayana, there are stories linking Kukai to the introduction to Japan of everything from green tea to ritualised homosexuality.) Shingon is sometimes known as mikkyo, or 'secret teaching', Buddhism, due to its complicated religious practices and perhaps the hardest doctrine to understand of all the major Japanese sects. At the same time, however, Shingon teaches that enlightenment can be obtained during a single lifetime (although unlike Jodo Shinshu and Nichiren, its teachings remain within the orthodox Buddhist nirvana model). Shingon's complicated practices, featuring mantras, mudras, mandalas, and some of the esoteric practices that were later passed on to Shugendo, made it a popular choice among Heian period (800s-1100s) Japanese nobles with lots of time on their hands and wishing to be reassured that they were doing just the right thing to achieve enlightenment. Although this exclusivity hurt Shingon in the long run, and it is not as popular in modern Japan as Jodo Shinshu or Nichiren, its spiritual 'capital' of Mount Koya is still a popular Buddhist retreat, and another of Kukai's legacies, the pilgrimage of the 88 Temples of Shikoku, is followed today by countless honourable pilgrims from around Japan and the world.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_SHUGENDO_SM">
			<Text>Shugendo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_SHUGENDO_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>Shugendo is a Japanese religion commonly associated with mountains and asceticism, made up of a sort of syncretic mixture of Shinto and Shintoesque folk practices, Shingon Buddhism, and Taoism. The founder of Shugendo is traditionally believed to have been En no Gyoja (634-c.707), a monk from the Nara region to whom superhuman powers are sometimes ascribed. Shugendo's mountain monks, or yamabushi, perform extreme, sometimes astounding, feats of faith in Japan's wilderness: standing under freezing waterfalls, hanging head-first over cliffs, climbing sheer rock walls, and so forth. The purpose of these rituals is, again, something not quite Shinto and not quite Buddhist, as the spirits of the mountains are mentioned as often as Buddhist-like practices such as meditation. The yamabushi also learnt, through their practices, to live on the mountains, and some of Shugendo's most notable temples are located on high peaks, and this ability led the yamabushi to take on other roles relating to the remotest areas of the country. This usually simply meant guiding people through the mountains, but they may have also acted as guerrillas on behalf of such leaders as Emperor Go-Daigo (who had his stronghold in the Shugendo heartland of the Kii Peninsula) and ancestors of some of Japan's first ninja. Although Shugendo suffered a seemingly fatal blow when it was outlawed by the State Shinto-adherent Meiji government in the 1860s, it has recently enjoyed something of a renaissance, as salarymen and the like seek to drop out of the regular rat race and don't find most religions quite intense enough for their weary spirits.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_SOKA_SM">
			<Text>Soka Gakkai</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_SOKA_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>It is hard to talk about Soka Gakkai, even define it, without attracting controversy from one side or the other. Starting from what should be the basics: Soka Gakkai is a religious organisation with over five million members in Japan, and perhaps as many as twelve million worldwide. Its teachings are said to be based on Nichiren Buddhism and the Lotus Sutra, but at the same time, it is effectively a splinter group, with frosty relations with the Nichiren orthodoxy despite being more successful than them in modern Japan. So the jury is sort of out on whether Soka Gakkai is a Buddhist sect or a cult. Supporting the former conclusion: their continued reliance on Nichiren teachings; their not-insignificant humanitarian outreach; their historical opposition to the 1930s junta; and the fact that they have seemingly blended into Japanese society without true religious tensions. Supporting the latter: various whistleblowers; the apparent fixation with their long-time leader, Daisaku Ikeda; the existence of their affiliated political party, Komeito, which spends its time endorsing rather un-Buddhist policies as the junior coalition partner to just about everyone; their suspiciously large coffers; and the name of their centrepiece building in Tokyo, the "Hall of the Great Vow for Kosen-rufu". Make up your own mind.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_STATE_SHINTO_SM">
			<Text>State Shinto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_STATE_SHINTO_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>State Shinto was the official religion - don't call it a religion, though - of the Japanese Empire from the Meiji Restoration to the end of the military junta (1868-1945). It was, by and large, a collection of existing beliefs and practices drawn from the previous centuries of 'Shinto' belief, tailored to suit the interests of the Imperial state. For example, the emperor, formally a fairly minor kami with only a few shrines, became the centrepiece of the new State Shinto, while Buddhism, a core part of the unified syncretic belief system of Japan for millennia, was forcibly and messily removed from the canon. At the same time, however, as the Meiji Constitution promised freedom of religion and diplomacy with the West involved not being too unfriendly to Western religions, State Shinto was officially classified as something other than a religion, with its shrines becoming secular centres of nationalistic fervour, dedicated only to those 'Shinto' ceremonies relating to the emperor and so forth.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Paradoxically, this period of supposedly 'pure' Shinto was a particularly bad time to be a priest or other practitioner of localised, religious, authentic Shinto. As State Shinto's government apparatus increasingly monopolised the attention the state gave to any sort of shrine, shrines that had existed for thousands of years were forced to change their purposes entirely to fit the ultranationalists, and eventually, non-State Shinto shrines were banned from having torii gates and their priests sometimes imprisoned. State Shinto met its swift end with the surrender of Japan in 1945, but it still has its fans on Japan's far right: Yasukuni Shrine, Japan's version of a national war memorial, is their most well-known haunt nowadays.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_TENDAI_SM">
			<Text>Tendai</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_TENDAI_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>Tendai is a school of Mahayana Buddhism, founded in its Japanese form in the year 806 by the monk Saicho, who had been studying a type of Buddhism known as Tiantai in China. Tendai doctrine holds that there is no true distinction between the mundane world and that of Buddhahood, and that everything in the world is ultimately an 'expression' of the Buddhist Law or Dharma. This lack of exclusivity in Tendai helped Japanese Buddhism reconcile with native religious practices, reaching a sort of compromise known as honji suijaku, wherein Shinto kami are seen as manifestations of Buddhas.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Although Tiantai was a fairly marginal school of Chinese Buddhism, its Japanese offshoot quickly became the favoured school of the nobility in Kyoto, Japan's new permanent capital. In accordance with the Japanese astrological belief that evil comes from a north-easterly direction, a large Tendai temple complex, Enryaku-ji, was built at the peak of Mount Hiei, north-east of Kyoto. The monks of Enryaku-ji wielded huge power over the Japanese religious establishment for centuries thereafter, up until Oda Nobunaga infamously destroyed the complex in 1582. Enryaku-ji has since been largely rebuilt, and is still an important centre of Japanese Buddhism, but Tendai never again reached the dominant position in Japan it had held in Heian times.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_TENRIKYO_SM">
			<Text>Tenrikyo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_TENRIKYO_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>Tenrikyo is one of the largest, oldest, and most prestigious of Japan's post-Meiji Restoration 'new religions', and thus, one of the few that has a claim to not being a cult. It was founded in the mid-1800s by Nakayama Miki, referred to by Tenrikyo followers as Oyasama, who is said to have had a divine revelation while trying to use Buddhist practices to heal her son's leg pains. While Tenrikyo includes elements familiar to both Shinto and Buddhism, other parts of it seem to be uniquely Tenrikyo, such as the belief in one single god (Tenri-o-no-mikoto) and the importance ascribed to the Jiba, a sacred spot seen to be the origin of the world and located within the religion's distinctive headquarters in central Nara Prefecture. Another aspect of Tenrikyo belief is the concept of 'innen', or causality, which is similar, but not identical to, Buddhist karma: while both Buddhism and Tenrikyo believe in a cycle of reincarnation, Buddhism places importance on the idea that the cycle can be escaped and eternal nirvana or Pure Land achieved, whereas in Tenrikyo the focus is on leading an ideal, upstanding, happily accepting, or "joyous" life within any given cycle.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_UTAKI_SM">
			<Text>Utakism</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_UTAKI_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>'Utakism' is the name given here to the indigenous religion of the Ryukyu Islands, known by many other names such as Utaki-shinko (an utaki being a sort of nature-based shrine) and Ryukyu Shinto. It has many similarities with mainland Japanese Shinto and Koshinto, although it is very unclear as to whether or not they actually share that close of an ancestry. The Ryukyuans maintained the tradition of women being seen as more spiritually powerful than men far longer than the mainlanders ever did, with an institutionalised system of female priestesses known as noro watching over local utaki and ultimately reporting to the Ryukyu Kingdom's seat of power at Shuri. Ryukyuan religion also ascribes importance to the idea of 'visiting' spirits, some of the many spirits and gods that form part of this religion, who descend to earth at certain times and bestow good fortune on, or ward off evil from, the inhabitants of wherever they land; the most known of these is probably Miruku, who descends from Nirai Kanai (a sort of Ryukyuan heaven) and is celebrated in numerous island festivals. Ryukyu's creation myth, centred around the goddess Amamikyu and the small island of Kudaka.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_YOSHIDA_SM">
			<Text>Yoshida Shinto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_YOSHIDA_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>Yoshida Shinto, or Yuiitsu ('the only' or 'exclusive') Shinto, is a type of Shinto founded by Yoshida Kanetomo of Kyoto in the late 1400s, around the time of the Onin War. Kanetomo, originally a bureaucrat dealing with Shinto affairs in the imperial court, developed a unique interpretation of Shinto featuring a unified theology (unusual, given the somewhat ad hoc nature of establishment Japanese syncretic Shinto-Buddhism). Although its rituals did in fact contain some elements with clearly Buddhist origins, Yoshida Shinto was perhaps the first major movement to explicitly reject Buddhism and point to an exclusively Shinto lineage supposedly descended from Amaterasu. Its prestige vis-a-vis 'regular', or Ise, Shinto grew dramatically as the Yoshida family became close to Toyotomi Hideyoshi in the late 1500s; eventually, the Yoshida had set themselves up as a sort of parallel centre for local shrine affairs across the country. It became common in the Edo period (1600-1868) for rural shrines to officially switch allegiances from Ise to Yoshida, thereby freeing themselves from Imperial bureaucracy along with any official taboos that may have been picked up along the way and which were seen as a hindrance to a better standard of living for villagers. The distinction between Ise and Yoshida Shinto essentially disappeared in the upheaval of the Meiji Restoration, although the chief Yoshida shrine still exists in Kyoto.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_ZEN_SM">
			<Text>Zen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_ZEN_SM_PEDIA">
			<Text>Zen is perhaps the most famous single school of Buddhism outside of Asia, and perhaps because of this, one of the most misunderstood. For example, the word Zen is often used to refer to Japanese Buddhism as a whole, whereas in reality, only about one fifth of Japan's temples are Zen, and the school is by no means the oldest in Japan. Rather, it was introduced in the Kamakura period (1192-1333) by two monks, Eisai and Dogen, who travelled to China and studied what was known as Chan Buddhism. A characteristically Zen practice its strong emphasis on meditation, in a broad sense of the term: Zen practitioners not only perform the classic sitting meditation (zazen) but also revere various art forms that can be meditative and reflective in their own way, such as Japanese tea ceremony. The school has twice been in the right place at the right time, in terms of the spread of its teachings; the first of these was with Hojo Tokimune, the Regent of Japan who was in power at the time of the Mongol invasions, who was devoutly Zen and spread the faith throughout the Japanese warrior classes. This is part of why Zen has had perhaps more of an influence on Japanese culture than any other sect: it may never have been the most popular sect, but it became the sect traditionally favoured by the most powerful in medieval Japanese society. (And yes, this is also why more leaders have Zen as their preference than any of the thirteen other Japanese religions in this mod!)[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The influence of Zen on medieval Japanese aristocratic culture, and thus its outsized footprint on Japan's human landscape (think rock gardens and the like), may have influenced its second break: the surge in interest in interpretations of Zen by Meiji-era Western-minded Japanese scholars such as D. T. Suzuki, along with their Western Japanologist counterparts, in the Western world in the 1950s and 1960s. Zen, which as mentioned before, genuinely did offer unique perspectives on activities not usually seen as religious, became seen as a sort of collection of ancient Japanese secrets to what was seen in the West as a new way of life. As a result, it became one of the most successful forms of Buddhism outside of its Asian heartland, to the extent that Zen in the West is now a multi-purpose adjective sometimes used to refer to things that have little to do with true Japanese Zen Buddhism.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_SM_SHINTO">
			<Text>Folk Shinto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_SM_SHINTO_PEDIA">
			<Text>Folk Shinto Pedia</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>