<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 1/16/2014 11:54:41 PM -->
<GameData>
  <Language_en_US>
		<!--Jaeger-->
	  <Delete Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_JAEGER_DESC" />
	  <Delete Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_JAEGER_TEXT" />
	  <Delete Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_JAEGER_STRATEGY" />
	  <Delete Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_JAEGER_HELP" />
	  <Delete Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_JAEGER" />
	  <Delete Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_JAEGER_HELP" />
	  <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_JAEGER_DESC">
		  <Text>Jaeger</Text>
	  </Row>
	  <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_JAEGER_TEXT">
		  <Text>Jäger is a German military term adopted in 1631 by the landgrave of Hesse when he first formed an elite infantry unit out of his professional hunters (Jäger) and rangers (Forstleute) in the Hessian Army. During the Age of Enlightenment in German-speaking states (and others influenced by them) Jäger is used to describe elite light infantry, especially skirmishers, scouts, sharpshooters and couriers. Jäger, which means "hunter" or "huntsman" in German, came by extension to denote light infantrymen whose forester background made them suitable for skirmishing as individuals rather than as a drilled and regimented body of soldiers. Often they came from families with a tradition of service to one feudal lord. Initially Jägers made use of their own precision made rifles: a more accurate weapon with a longer range than the muskets used by line troops.</Text>
	  </Row>
	  <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_JAEGER_STRATEGY">
		  <Text>The Jaeger is the unique German replacement for the Rifleman. Unlike the Rifleman, the Jaeger begins with the Scouting 1 and Survivalism 1 promotions, and so can be upgraded with promotions normally only available to Recon units, such as the Scout. It also earns promotions 15% faster.</Text>
	  </Row>
	  <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_JAEGER_HELP">
		  <Text>Begins with Scouting 1 and Survivalism 1. May earn promotions normally only available to Recon units. Earns promotions 15% faster.</Text>
	  </Row>
	  <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_JAEGER">
		  <Text>Feldjäger</Text>
	  </Row>
	  <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_JAEGER_HELP">
		  <Text>Earns 15% more experience from combat.</Text>
	  </Row>
  </Language_en_US>
</GameData>