<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 5/2/2019 12:10:29 AM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--Civilization, Leader & Pedias-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_PB_LIBERTATIA_DESC">
			<Text>Colony of Libertatia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_PB_LIBERTATIA_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Libertatia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_PB_LIBERTATIA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Liberi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_PB_LIBERTATIA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Geography and Climate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_PB_LIBERTATIA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>As a result of the island's long isolation from neighboring continents, Madagascar is home to various plants and animals found nowhere else on Earth. Approximately 90% of all plant and animal species found in Madagascar are endemic. This distinctive ecology has led some ecologists to refer to Madagascar as the "eighth continent", and the island has been classified by Conservation International as a biodiversity hotspot.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The combination of southeastern trade winds and northwestern monsoons produces a hot rainy season with frequently destructive cyclones, and a relatively cooler dry season. Rain clouds originating over the Indian Ocean discharge much of their moisture over the island's eastern coast; the heavy precipitation supports the area's rainforest ecosystem. The central highlands are both drier and cooler while the west is drier still, and a semi-arid climate prevails in the southwest and southern interior of the island.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_PB_LIBERTATIA_HEADING_2">
			<Text>European and Arab Piracy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_PB_LIBERTATIA_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Madagascar was an important transoceanic trading hub connecting ports of the Indian Ocean in the early centuries following human settlement. The written history of Madagascar began with the Arabs, who established trading posts along the northwest coast by at least the 10th century and introduced Islam, the Arabic script (used to transcribe the Malagasy language in a form of writing known as sorabe), Arab astrology, and other cultural elements. European contact began in 1500, when the Portuguese sea captain Diogo Dias sighted the island. The French established trading posts along the east coast in the late 17th century.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]From about 1774 to 1824, Madagascar gained prominence among pirates and European traders, particularly those involved in the trans-Atlantic slave trade. The small island of Nosy Boroha (Île Sainte-Marie) off the northeastern coast of Madagascar has been proposed by some historians as the site of the legendary pirate utopia of Libertatia. Many European sailors were shipwrecked on the coasts of the island, among them Robert Drury, whose journal is one of the few written depictions of life in southern Madagascar during the 18th century. The wealth generated by maritime trade spurred the rise of organized kingdoms on the island, some of which had grown quite powerful by the 17th century. Among these were the Betsimisaraka alliance of the eastern coast and the Sakalava chiefdoms of Menabe and Boina on the west coast. The Kingdom of Imerina, located in the central highlands with its capital at the royal palace of Antananarivo, emerged at around the same time under the leadership of King Andriamanelo.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_PB_LIBERTATIA_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Libertatia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_PB_LIBERTATIA_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Libertatia was a legendary free colony forged by pirates and the pirate Captain Misson, although some historians have expressed doubts over its existence outside of literature. Libertatia got its name from the latin word Liberi which means "free". Misson's idea was to have his society be a society in which people of all colors, creeds, and beliefs were to be free of any scrutiny. He wanted to give the people of Libertatia their own demonym, not one of a past country of origin.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The pirates were against the various forms of authoritarian social constructs of their day, monarchies, slavery, and capital. The pirates practiced forms of direct democracy, where the people as a whole held the authority to make laws and rules, and used systems of councils with delegates, who were supposed to think of themselves as "comrades" of the general population, and not rulers. The pirates created a new language for their colony and operated a socialist economy.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_PB_LIBERTATIA_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Historicity</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_PB_LIBERTATIA_TEXT_4">
			<Text>The consensus of modern scholarship is that Libertatia was not a real place. Journalist Kevin Rushby toured the area seeking descendants of pirate inhabitants but declined to search the jungles for Libertatia, noting “others have tried and failed many times.” There were pirate settlements on and around Madagascar, on which Libertatia may have been based: Abraham Samuel at Port Dauphin, Adam Baldridge at Ile Ste.-Marie, and James Plaintain at Ranter Bay were all ex-pirates who founded trading posts and towns. These locations appear frequently in official accounts and letters from the period, while Libertatia appears only in Johnson’s General History, Volume 2. Defoe writes about the overall set up of Libertatia. The settlement was proposed to have an elevated fort on each side of the harbor with 40 guns in each fort, from the Portuguese. Below the fort, under the protection of the forts, was where the living quarters along with the rest of the town was located. Libertatia was located roughly 13 miles east-south-east of the nearest of the nearest civilization. However, the overall location is deemed to be completely fictional.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_PB_LIBERTATIA_TEXT">
			<Text>Avast, Monsieur James Misson, Captain of the Victoire and Lord Conservator of the ideal colony of Libertatia! You were born to an ancient French family in Provence, receiving a good education and showing exceptional command of logic and the humanities. After completing your studies you were accepted as a volunteer on the Man-of-war Victoire, where at the urging of the priest Caraccioli you worked your way up to Captain and earned the respect of your men. After several adventures at sea and the expansion of your pirate fleet, you set sail for Madagascar and there established the pirate haven of Libertatia.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Captain Misson, Libertatia is free from the yoke of tyranny, and no hedge may bound any man's particular property. The pirates that live full and free lives call upon you again to protect their home! Can you inspire them to raise the flag and take their prizes with honor and gallantry? Can you nurture the age of "Piracy without tears"? Can you build a Civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON">
			<Text>James Misson</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_NAME">
			<Text>James Misson</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Libertatia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Captain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_TITLES_2">
			<Text>Lord Conservator</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_LIVED">
			<Text>17th Century</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Early Life</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>James Misson was born to an ancient French family of Provence. He was the youngest of a large family, and received a good education. t the age of 15 he had already shown unusual distinction in the subjects of humanity and logic, and had passed quite tolerably in mathematics. Deciding to carve a fortune for himself with his sword, he was sent to the Academy at Angiers for a year, and at the conclusion of his military studies his father would have bought him a commission in a regiment of musketeers. But young Misson had been reading books of travel, and begged so earnestly to be allowed to go to sea that his father got him admitted as a volunteer on the French man-of-war Victoire, commanded by Monsieur Fourbin. Joining his ship at Marseilles, they cruised in the Mediterranean, and the young volunteer soon showed great keenness in his duties, and lost no opportunity of learning all he could about navigation and the construction of ships, even parting with his pocket-money to the boatswain and the carpenter to receive special instruction from them.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Caraccioli and the Victoire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_TEXT_2">
			<Text>It happened that while in Rome the young sailor met a priest, a Signor Caraccioli, a Dominican, who held most unclerical views about the priesthood; and, indeed, his ideas on life in general were, to say the least, unorthodox. A great friendship was struck up between these two, which at length led the priest to throw off his habit and join the crew of the Victoire. Two days out from port they met and fought a desperate hand-to-hand engagement with a Sallee pirate, in which the ex-priest and Misson both distinguished themselves by their bravery. Misson's next voyage was in a privateer, the Triumph, and, meeting one day an English ship, the Mayflower, between Guernsey and Start Point, the merchantman was defeated after a gallant resistance.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rejoining the Victoire, Misson sailed from Rochelle to the West Indies, and Caraccioli lost no opportunity of preaching to young Misson the gospel of atheism and communism, and with such success that the willing convert soon held views as extreme as those of his teacher. These two apostles now began to talk to the crew, and their views, particularly on the rights of private property, were soon held by almost all on board. A fortunate event happened just then to help the new "cause." Meeting with an English man-of-war, the Winchester, off the island of Martinique, a smart engagement took place between the two ships, at the very commencement of which Captain Fourbin and three of the officers on the French ship were killed. The fight ended by the English ship blowing up, and an era of speech-making may be said to have now begun. Firstly, Signor Caraccioli, stepping forward, made a long and eloquent address to Misson, inviting him to become captain of the Victoire, and calling upon him to follow the example of Alexander the Great with the Persians, and that of the Kings Henry IV. and VII. of England, reminding him how Mahomet, with but a few camel-drivers, founded the Ottoman Empire, also how Darius, with a handful of companions, got possession of Persia. Inflamed by this speech, young Misson showed what he could do, when, calling all hands up on deck, he made his first, but, as events proved, by far from last, speech. The result was a triumph of oratory, the excited French sailors crying out: "Vive le Capitaine Misson et son Lieutenant le Scavant Caraccioli!"</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Libertatia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Misson took his followers to a sheltered bay in Madagascar, and upon landing there made a speech to his men. Here they could settle down, build a town, and "have some place to call their own; and a Receptacle, when Age or Wounds had render'd them incapable of Hardship, where they might enjoy the Fruits of their Labour, and go to their Graves in Peace."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]This ideal colony was called Libertatia, and was run on socialist lines. No-one owned any invididual property, all money was kept in a communal treasury, and no hedges bounded any man's particular plot of land. Docks were made and fortifications were set up. Soon Misson had two ships built, called the Childhood and the Liberty, and these were sent for a voyage round the island, to map and chart the coast, and to train the released slaves to be efficient sailors. A Session House was built, and a form of Government arranged. At the first meeting Misson was elected Lord Conservator, as they called the President, for a term of three years, and during that period he was to have "all the Ensigns of Royalty to attend him." Captain Tew, the English pirate, was elected Admiral of the Fleet of Libertatia, Caraccioli became Secretary of State, while the Council was formed of the ablest amongst the pirates, without distinction of nation or colour. The difficulty of language, as French, English, Portuguese, and Dutch were equally spoken, was overcome by the invention of a new language, a kind of Esperanto, which was built up of words from all four.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Death</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MISSON_PEDIA_TEXT_4">
			<Text>For many years this ideally successful and happy pirate Utopia flourished; but at length misfortunes came, one on top of the other, and a sudden and unexpected attack by the hitherto friendly natives finally drove Misson and a few other survivors to seek safety at sea, but, overtaken by a hurricane, their vessel foundered, and Misson and all his crew were drowned; and thus ended the era of what may be called "piracy without tears."</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_PB_PIRATE_ROUND">
			<Text>Worked Farms adjacent to another Farm provide Great Admiral Points. Defeating enemy Naval Units may create civilian "Plunder" ships, which yield large amounts of [ICON_GOLD] Gold and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture if returned to a City.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_PB_PIRATE_ROUND_SHORT">
			<Text>The Pirate Round</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_PB_PIRATE_ROUND_NOTIFICATION">
			<Text>Your Cities have produced +{1_Num} [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great Admiral Points from adjacent Farms!</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--City Names-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_1">
			<Text>Île Sainte-Marie</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_2">
			<Text>Ranter Bay</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_3">
			<Text>Fort Dauphine</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_4">
			<Text>Antongil Bay</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_5">
			<Text>Johanna</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_6">
			<Text>Saint-Augustin Bay</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_7">
			<Text>Tamatave</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_8">
			<Text>Port Chorseul</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_9">
			<Text>Cap Saint-André</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_10">
			<Text>Andrava Bay</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_11">
			<Text>Cap Kimby</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_12">
			<Text>Tulear</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_13">
			<Text>Diego-Suarez</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_14">
			<Text>Cap Saint-Vincent</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_15">
			<Text>Mananjary</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_16">
			<Text>Fénérive</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_17">
			<Text>Vohémar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_18">
			<Text>Maintirano</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_19">
			<Text>Cap Namakia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_20">
			<Text>Foulepointe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_21">
			<Text>Port Saint-Felix</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_22">
			<Text>Managuara</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_23">
			<Text>Lahefonti</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_24">
			<Text>Île Sainte-Claire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_25">
			<Text>Didan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_26">
			<Text>Morigambo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_27">
			<Text>Île Sainte-Luce</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_28">
			<Text>Cap de l'Est</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_29">
			<Text>Île aux Prunes</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Spy Names-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_0">
			<Text>Caraccioli</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_1">
			<Text>Thomas Tew</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_2">
			<Text>Mathew le Tondu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_3">
			<Text>Abraham Samuel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_4">
			<Text>James Plantain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_5">
			<Text>Edward England</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_6">
			<Text>Adam Baldridge</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_7">
			<Text>John Avery</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_8">
			<Text>Samuel Burgess</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_PB_LIBERTATIA_9">
			<Text>John Halsey</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Units-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_PB_MANOFWAR">
			<Text>Man-of-war</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_PB_MANOFWAR_HELP">
			<Text>Gains +30% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength in Ocean tiles that are not owned by a Civilization. If a Man-of-war begins its turn stacked with a civilian Unit, it will grant the civilian double [ICON_MOVES] Movement. Replaces the Privateer.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_PB_MANOFWAR_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Man-of-war is a Liberi unique unit, replacing the Privateer. In addition to normal effects, it is 30% stronger when in neutral Ocean territory. At the beginning of its turn, the Man-of-war will grant any civilian units stacked with it double Movement points.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_PB_MANOFWAR_TEXT">
			<Text>Man-of-war is not a specific class of ship; instead, it was British nomenclature for any large, armed ship propelled by sails rather than by oars. They were often used to transport large numbers of soldiers, hence the origin of the designation "Man-of-war". The ships referred to as such originated in the 15th century and continued on into the golden ages of exploration and piracy.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_PB_PLUNDER">
			<Text>Plunder</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_PB_PLUNDER_HELP">
			<Text>Plunder captured from a defeated enemy vessel. Return it safely to a port City for a large boost of [ICON_GOLD] Gold and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_PB_PLUNDER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Plunder may be seized when Libertatia destroys an enemy Naval Unit. Although only Libertatia can create Plunder ships, any Civilization may capture them once they have been spawned. Keep Plunder ships well-guarded, and guide them safely back to a port City to reap rewards of Gold and Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_PB_PLUNDER_TEXT">
			<Text>Illegally acquired property is referred to as "plunder". During the age of piracy, it was common for ships to be boarded and to have their cargo and valuables seized, and in some cases the ship itself would be commandeered.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_POLICY_PB_PLUNDER">
			<Text>Plunder</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Promotions -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_PB_MOW_OCEAN_COMBAT">
			<Text>Open Ocean</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_PB_MOW_GIVES_MOVEMENT">
			<Text>Haulier</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_PB_MOW_OCEAN_COMBAT_HELP">
			<Text>+30% Combat Strength in open Ocean.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_PB_MOW_GIVES_MOVEMENT_HELP">
			<Text>Grants double Movement to stacked civilian units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Buildings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PB_SESSION_HOUSE">
			<Text>Session House</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDING_PB_SESSION_HOUSE_TEXT">
			<Text>A session house was built in Libertatia to house the pirate utopia's government facilities. Mission was elected Lord Conservator at the session house for a three-year term, during which he was afforded "All the Ensigns of Royalty". Docks were built close to the session house where two ships were constructed - "Childhood" and "Liberty".</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PB_SESSION_HOUSE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Session House is the Liberi unique building, replacing the Harbor. In addition to normal effects, the Session House grants [ICON_CULTURE] Culture from all sea resources and an extra 1% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production toward Naval Units for every Social Policy unlocked by Libertatia (up to a maximum of 20%).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PB_SESSION_HOUSE_HELP">
			<Text>Unique Liberi Harbor replacement. +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture from Sea Resources, and +1% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production towards Naval Units for each Social Policy unlocked.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]City must be built on the coast.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PB_LIB_ADMIRAL_POINTS_DUMMY">
			<Text>Libertatia Admiral Dummy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PB_LIB_ADMIRAL_POINTS_DUMMY_HELP">
			<Text>Gives Libertatia GA points from farm adjacency.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PB_LIB_SH_PROD_DUMMY">
			<Text>Libertatia Session House Dummy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PB_LIB_SH_PROD_DUMMY_HELP">
			<Text>Gives Libertatia naval production from Social Policies.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>